<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ming Y. Chow</title>
    <description>Ming Chow's website
</description>
    <link>https://mchow01.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://mchow01.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 15:05:16 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 15:05:16 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Students' Summer Internship Reports, In Their Own Words</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I run the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ase.tufts.edu/icenter/immigration/employment/offCampus_F1_cpt.asp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Curricular Practical Training (CPT)&lt;/a&gt; program for international students for the Computer Science Department at Tufts.  This program is necessary for international students to do a summer internship.  As part of getting credit for CPT, I ask each student to write a report addressing: (1) what did student learn technically, (2) what did student learn professionally, (3) what did student wish supervisor(s) did differently, and (4) what would student have done differently.  This summer, there were 18 students in CPT and the reports produced were awesome. Lots of fantastic stories, lessons learned.  The stories illustrate what students are getting out of our curriculum and ultimately in the academic environment, what students are not getting out of our curriculum, and the importance of having professional experience to go along with the academics.  Some gems to share (names and companies, institutions redacted):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I also realized that I liked the freedom of open-ended problems a lot more than problems in class. My supervisor would explain the problem to me, would give me pointers as to where to start looking at and give me some of the initial ideas he had. But he left much of the engineering to me. I got used to just experimenting my ideas, which felt more motivating.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Although I could never had known this at the start of my internship, I do wish that I was used to reading research papers.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“One of my first mistakes was to think that the supervisor expected me to know everything beforehand and that asking questions was something to be ashamed of.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“As such, I was unprepared for the practical knowledge that went into and the scale of [redacted] infrastructure and tooling. On the first day, my team members rattled off no less than five different systems that they were maintaining”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Secondly, I developed my communication skills and understood the importance of communication both at a work-related and non-work-related level.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Next, I learned that I should not expect my supervisor or manager to give me all the instructions I need”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I also learned to not feel ashamed when asking the person who wrote the code you are working with how it works.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“…the first thing to do in creating an application is to make it work first and then optimization should come later.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I would have taken some more breaks this summer. As this internship is wrapping up I’ve been completing some of the final touches to my projects but I can’t help but feel a little burned out.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“First off how important it is to enjoy your workplace culture and the companionship of your colleagues. I am very fortunate to be able to work with people that bring a smile onto my face everyday and laughter into the workplace.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“And by having someone professionally QA my work, made me realized the importance of the safety of the code, and never ever trust user’s input.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The only feedback that I have received was when I explicitly asked to meet and to discuss about how I’m doing.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The working process promotes the heavy use of the revision control software Git, with which each developer works on different feature branches for different projects before having their code meticulously reviewed by various members of the team for quality check and then sent to the Quality Assurance team for testing.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I also learned to ask relevant and timely questions so as to facilitate my initial learning process without delaying the work of my supervisor and coworkers.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“On the job, no one but myself could be my teacher.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I wish my supervisor could use less jargons and more plain English when he answered my questions.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It is important to keep focus on your own project, but it is equally important to get known more about your colleagues’ projects. I think this could help me find more things I feel interested about.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I wish I could have gone over the [redacted] API documentation more thoroughly before I started working on the app”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I also wish I could have asked more of my coworkers’ help”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“How to engage with and seek help from anyone who might know more about something than I do.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I wish I had a chance to discuss the results with my advisor or collaborators from medical poi_nt of view. I believe this step was necessary to validate the result of the project. Networking with more people in my research field is another item I can mention as an important aspect of the internship that I wish I had worked on more.”_&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I hope I could design the project clearly first, and make sure I understand every part, then start writing code.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Besides just writing code, I have also had regular meetings with both my supervisors and my clients from the Recruitment Department to showcase, discuss, and improve on existing features and create a better user’s experience. What I have realized through those meetings is that effective communication is essential to any successful project.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Moreover, I wish I could have asked for help more often than trying to solve some problem by myself for a long time, as I could have been problem-solving more efficiently.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Thus, I learned that I should be always ready to presenting my work to others.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Communicating your ideas is very important to work in a team.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://mchow01.github.io/career/2017/08/16/summer-internship-reports.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mchow01.github.io/career/2017/08/16/summer-internship-reports.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>career</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hall of Shame Job Postings and Recruiting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We constantly hear that cyber security has a serious talent shortage.  It doesn’t help when job descriptions are completely asinine or when recruiting is embarrassingly bad.  This also goes for the tech industry in general.  After reading these tweets from my friend Ed Rojas, I decided to dedicate a hall of shame to this ongoing problem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Just read this req on LinkedIn: Masters in cybersecurity + 2 high level certs + Risk Analysis, Ethical Hacking, Incident Response, 1/2&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; SilverFox (@EdgarR0jas) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EdgarR0jas/status/897529699290800128&quot;&gt;August 15, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Security architect, BCP/DR, Forensic Analyst, SOC design/implementation. Only reply if you meet all requirements. Seriously????? 2/2&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; SilverFox (@EdgarR0jas) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EdgarR0jas/status/897529959656194048&quot;&gt;August 15, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another purpose of this post is to back up the arguments made in the article: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tripwire.com/state-of-security/risk-based-security-for-executives/connecting-security-to-the-business/there-is-no-cyber-talent-crunch-youre-just-hiring-wrong/&quot;&gt;“There Is No Cyber Talent Crunch; You’re Just Hiring Wrong”&lt;/a&gt; especially the points of “insisting on over-qualified applicants” and over-filtering.  There are many job candidates who &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AdrianCohea/status/899503146153656321&quot;&gt;“are feeling utterly demoralized for no reason”&lt;/a&gt; especially after seeing such job postings.  A message that I want to make clear with this post: don’t disqualify yourself –because the purple squirrel does not exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;who-the-hell-are-they-going-to-find-these-jobs-on-a-contract-basis-good-luck-creating-and-updating-all-those-documents-in-six-months-thanks-to-tcstoolhax0r-for-this&quot;&gt;Who the hell are they going to find these jobs on a contract basis? Good luck creating and updating all those documents in six months (thanks to @tcstoolHax0r for this)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_002.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_006.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quite-a-lot-of-requirements-good-luck-finding-someone-thanks-to-tcstoolhax0r-for-this&quot;&gt;Quite a lot of requirements, good luck finding someone (thanks to @tcstoolHax0r for this)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_004.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-an-entire-infosec-department-in-one-engineer-thanks-triggs390&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Triggs390/status/898023922075140096&quot;&gt;“It’s an entire InfoSec department in one engineer!”&lt;/a&gt; (thanks @Triggs390)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_003.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-on-earth-is-cyber-awareness-and-understanding-thanks-to-tcstoolhax0r-for-this&quot;&gt;What on earth is “cyber awareness and understanding”? (thanks to @tcstoolHax0r for this)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_005.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;someone-didnt-even-read-the-resume-thanks-to-tcstoolhax0r-for-this&quot;&gt;Someone didn’t even read the resume (thanks to @tcstoolHax0r for this)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_008.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-need-to-have-all-those-certifications-thanks-to-tcstoolhax0r-for-this&quot;&gt;I need to have all those certifications? (thanks to @tcstoolHax0r for this)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;this-is-for-an-internship-first-selenium-is-misspelled--another-one-of-these-nda-clowns--to-top-it-all-off-at-present-we-are-exceeding-our-expectations-dafuq-thanks-to-marsella_h-for-this&quot;&gt;This is for an internship. First, Selenium is misspelled.  Another one of these NDA clowns.  To top it all off: “At present we are exceeding our expectations” –dafuq (thanks to @marsella_h for this)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_009.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the only statement that is missing from the above posting is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/we-showed-great-character.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;We showed great character&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;there-is-no-such-thing-as-a-giac-certified-ethical-hacker-certification-thanks-to-tcstoolhax0r-for-this&quot;&gt;There is no such thing as a GIAC Certified Ethical Hacker certification (thanks to @tcstoolHax0r for this)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_011.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-was-trying-to-find-evidence-of-the-job-opening-that-requires-8-years-of-swift-experience-to-no-avail-but-i-did-find-this-terribly-written-job-ad-for-a-senior-ios-developer-10-years-of-experience-required-but-marked-as-junior-experience&quot;&gt;I was trying to find evidence of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kevinkaywho/status/898622008019124224&quot;&gt;job opening that requires 8+ years of Swift experience&lt;/a&gt; to no avail, but I did find this terribly written job ad for a Senior iOS Developer (10+ years of experience required) but marked as “junior” experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_012.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;third-point-down-this-is-what-happens-when-recruiters-use-buzzwords-with-no-idea-what-they-mean-aws--amazon-web-services-azure-belongs-to-microsoft-thanks-to-cthulhusec-for-this&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CthulhuSec/status/900318071713398784&quot;&gt;“Third point down. This is what happens when recruiters use buzzwords with no idea what they mean.” AWS = Amazon Web Services, Azure belongs to Microsoft (thanks to @CthulhuSec for this)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_013.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mother-of-god-we-save-the-best-for-last-as-we-hit-the-jackpot-with-this-one-three-years-as-a-developer-plus-5-years-at-least-in-all-the-other-domains-in-total-55-years-experience-for-the-optimum-candidate-thanks-to-sprkyco-for-this-gem&quot;&gt;Mother of God! We save the best for last as we hit the jackpot with this one. “Three years as a developer plus 5 years at least in all the other domains. In total ~55 years experience for the optimum candidate.” (thanks to @sprkyco for this gem)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_010.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;addendum&quot;&gt;Addendum&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend Rob Graham wrote this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Remember: a lot of recruiting posts are designed so that nobody can fill them - except for that one foreigner you&amp;#39;ve already decided to hire&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rob Graham٩(●̮̮̃●̃) (@ErrataRob) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ErrataRob/status/898015231309262848&quot;&gt;August 17, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there is truth in what Rob wrote, the problem is when recruiters spam the same job description everywhere (e.g., on LinkedIn) which wastes everyone’s time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 21:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://mchow01.github.io/career/2017/08/16/hall-of-shame-job-postings-recruiting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mchow01.github.io/career/2017/08/16/hall-of-shame-job-postings-recruiting.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>career</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Results of a Password Cracking Contest for My Online Security Class (Summer 2017)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I offered my &lt;a href=&quot;https://tuftsdev.github.io/DefenseAgainstTheDarkArts&quot;&gt;Introduction to Computer Security&lt;/a&gt; class as an online course for the first time.  I give a month-long summer lab to crack as many passwords as possible.  For this summer’s contest &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/0xmchow/status/882073476886089731&quot;&gt;(opened on July 3, 2017&lt;/a&gt;), I used three different hash types: NTLM, MD5, and SHA-512.  The password hashes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
chicagobear:$1$P3QnPJRC$ZiUGVezmZmHP3FwGBrSvx0:1003:1003:,,,:/home/chicagobear:/bin/bash
bigbear:$1$0HXmPq6a$b6SJ9SFllGgOz2dU/J1t1.:1004:1004:,,,:/home/bigbear:/bin/bash
jojobear:$1$iSCIcnDl$GhUJv320ZA7aEkmFlLBRb/:1005:1005:,,,:/home/jojobear:/bin/bash
crazybear:$1$Ojbempgo$5GSSpK2r2McB8pyfhsEiy0:1006:1006:,,,:/home/crazybear:/bin/bash
slothbear:$1$nTQQPLJE$go2/.YC/4evqQKE4fPIiB0:1007:1007:,,,:/home/slothbear:/bin/bash
cocobear:$1$xLkX79Xq$gVMgVkhzjkGODtL79NgLY0:1008:1008:,,,:/home/cocobear:/bin/bash
willybear:$1$RdCmq9HN$YhybIiTYwSjywxTotYub4/:1009:1009:,,,:/home/willybear:/bin/bash
yogibear:$1$s.vVsfIL$YWZ.49mClunDlkJapYKZ1/:1010:1010:,,,:/home/yogibear:/bin/bash
blackbear:$6$xGcUMQHK$eOPlvJwoLa3BIrDwHb9k5g3TyukWnmMgXlG6rXc/JiEeBTQ1GMzbm.6jHsxO1ofsMp.PbTVdMQqKDIlCQcfmz0:1000:1000:,,,:/home/blackbear:/bin/bash
blinkybear:$6$Ga52kSM3$3T6ri0./UFR6V/6ICzMX1wB.GG26eKpP2HhaQUpQKTzKfSwqWaTK4CX8kyjwZZA4PH2ns5oH6SrxHMImg.kfb/:1001:1001:,,,:/home/blinkybear:/bin/bash
cacabear:$6$GSEyFgvt$CUjBn1cspBlxmi0YZbFHs.JfR/6FIzh8RRUMhXIYQZXherSbluLlehghZ3Yi2Su2TazjMg3aRNj4V9mWDyhgA1:1002:1002:,,,:/home/cacabear:/bin/bash
cozybear:$6$QklnyMgo$b0MQ9qJwyCjVG7txLANcH2a49h/f5KcA5eoS82T7IKRJqmGWHqO8F5tadHukuibwoUitj5ctQLVX2DXk94vkK/:1003:1003:,,,:/home/cozybear:/bin/bash
yetibear:$6$.u.lAiwI$ZQ1gWfUkquUoSjgjHQsyty.bRvXUYtuSLjLgZYvlQ.fZz6R.4zHPFqcfeqsaCUBH.P9IbZn4wHGyOADfrbiS1/:1004:1004:,,,:/home/yetibear:/bin/bash
grizzlybear:$6$dslx5A3f$g3OVHjyw.2X1gp/C55bHu.s6WRzZD5Iu5j0/3lCMRfnh.fNzyMArQZn56J2J/tB2EG0iKHQnz62pNAtHBt0yk.:1005:1005:,,,:/home/grizzlybear:/bin/bash
smokeybear:$6$yY5UKBjz$wINjW.wdjzaFHD6ytdOGFPjzUoUrRN1dGtr4iNU93/hTVVXO/pqG18nhopZX/7Koc.A3l2kLSxWhykQUFUGF0/:1006:1006:,,,:/home/smokeybear:/bin/bash
fozziebear:$6$K.BwBqhO$NVW0itQwjECKIbPjHy9b6qys2lv92r6ExvIzSA9dhIUKdvHO223ud7fr7JYLHQ1R9dW.ziMNWX4vd.QfsY3vk1:1007:1007:,,,:/home/fozziebear:/bin/bash
Administrator:500:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:e19ccf75ee54e06b06a5907af13cef42:::
fancybear:1009:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:be1773ca5eccc0102006d0f12ee9aeba:::
pedrobear:1000:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:572954208e36c94da325117731186344:::
polarbear:1003:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:8c1653757cb5205609a524b1b3e1c5f7:::
teddybear:1004:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:ebb2b64f58ade30183b2155a567b1c7a:::
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I combed through the submissions today: 23 total submissions (students can submit multiple times but only the last submission will count).  The answers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
(MD5) chicagobear:P1rate$ =&amp;gt; 5 students cracked this
(MD5) bigbear:Va-[B~ =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(MD5) jojobear:SRYSQF =&amp;gt; 1 student cracked this
(MD5) crazybear:mrfVlkECv =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(MD5) slothbear:L!verpool =&amp;gt; 4 students cracked this
(MD5) cocobear:CCc3 =&amp;gt; 4 students cracked this
(MD5) willybear:wGPLek =&amp;gt; 1 student cracked this
(MD5) yogibear:rqb3Hc =&amp;gt; 1 student cracked this
(SHA512) blackbear:dave =&amp;gt; 22 students cracked this
(SHA512) blinkybear:zUnR =&amp;gt; 1 student cracked this
(SHA512) cacabear:/|rv]y =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(SHA512) cozybear:is0g0TriE =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(SHA512) yetibear:thx1138 =&amp;gt; 22 students cracked this
(SHA512) grizzlybear:extreme =&amp;gt; 20 students cracked this
(SHA512) smokeybear:B00ty =&amp;gt; 2 students cracked this
(SHA512) fozziebear:PCMASTERRACE =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(NTLM) Administrator: P@ssw0rd =&amp;gt; 9 students cracked this
(NTLM) pedrobear:JJyI8f3MG =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(NTLM) polarbear:HomerSimpson1 =&amp;gt; 4 students cracked this
(NTLM) teddybear:K-(*4@ =&amp;gt; 3 students cracked this
(NTLM) fancybear:6F2Xx2f6 =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winner cracked 11 of the passwords.  The student’s haul:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
jojobear:SRYSQF
cocobear:CCc3
willybear:wGPLek
yogibear:rqb3Hc
blackbear:dave
blinkybear:zUnR
grizzlybear:extreme
smokeybear:B00ty
yetibear:thx1138
Administrator:P@ssw0rd
teddybear:K-(*4@
&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 21:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://mchow01.github.io/education/security/2017/08/15/password-cracking.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mchow01.github.io/education/security/2017/08/15/password-cracking.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Best Thing To Do In Early Summer for Undergraduates: Prepare For Opportunities Next Summer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the best thing undergraduates can do in the early summer: prepare for the opportunity next summer –whether you currently have an internship / research opportunity or not.  There is no substitute for real experience.  Experience and track record are paramount for any opportunity from first full-time opportunity out of college to senior-level position. &lt;em&gt;How can people trust you and your work when you have little or nothing to show for?&lt;/em&gt;  Case-in-point, on Turner Construction’s website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.turnerconstruction.com/careers/campus/internships&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;“In today’s competitive professional world, the most qualified job candidates have more than classroom experience. They leave college and enter the workforce with hands-on exposure in their chosen fields. Turner places high value on internship experience when making hiring decisions.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My career advice to undergraduate students is to get experience early and often.  Chantel McCabe said it best: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tnhdigital.com/8185/news/tnh-alumni-series-chantel-mccabe-11/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I interned every single semester. No classroom curriculum can replace the lessons you learn by doing and interacting. The most difficult part is getting acclimated: knowing where to go and who to go to for what and feeling comfortable.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  Many undergraduates do not realize the enormous payoff of working and gaining experience early including higher pay and retroactive accrual of benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you currently have an internship, you already have an advantage but that does not mean you should be too comfortable.  If you have already made an impact and people around you know it, good chance you will be offered a full-time opportunity after graduation or be asked to return next summer.  I have even seen undergraduates being asked to quit school and work full-time.  This is a good time to ask yourself a few important questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you see yourself continuing the work that you are doing?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you like the people who you are working with?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If offered the opportunity to return next summer, would you stay?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If graduate school is on your radar for the future, another consideration is to do summer research via Research Experience for Undergraduates (REU).  That will give you first hand research experience, perhaps a publication opportunity which will give you a significant advantage over other graduate school applicants in the future, and you will still get to build stuff.  Example: my friend and colleague Ben Shapiro at the University of Colorado, Boulder currently have two summer REU students building a framework for real-time machine learning in browser, using web-Bluetooth to get input from tangible devices.  That skillset is incredibly valuable for future opportunities, industry or academia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you currently do not have an internship, early summer is the perfect time to start preparing for your search for opportunities for next summer.  Action items on how to take advantage of the time that you have:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Go to meetups and networking events (this also include conferences).&lt;/strong&gt;  The warm weather makes way for more events.  The importance of networking events:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You meet people who could be your future employer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You meet people who are like you and perhaps in the same situation as you are.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You meet people in the field you are interested in getting into and what the community is like.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can listen to similar or different perspectives and ideas. For example, if you have an idea for a side project, someone may tell you the pitfalls or proceeding with the idea.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You have the opportunity learn something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Side note: my friend Greg Raiz runs Drinks On Tap.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/DrinksOnTap/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Drinks On Tap is a social meet up for the mobile developer community.&lt;/a&gt;  If you want to get into Cyber Security, there is the &lt;a href=&quot;/security/2015/07/19/security-summer-camp.html&quot;&gt;trio of infamous conferences in Las Vegas a.k.a., summer security camp&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;Start making a list companies that you want to talk to at a fall career fair.&lt;/strong&gt;  While you may not know who will be at the fall career fair, you can base it on the list of institutions and companies at the previous year's fall career fair.  Many companies / institutions and recruiters are now only focusing on the fall career fair and not going to the spring career fair.  The reason: competition for talent is fierce and companies / institutions want to fill their summer slots early with the best possible talents.  Alas, I hear many students say that when they went to the spring career fair, it was slim pickings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;Keep yourself busy.&lt;/strong&gt;  If you receive an interview for an opportunity for next summer and your resume has gaps, you can bet you will be asked the question or something of-the-like: &quot;What did you do last summer?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4. &lt;strong&gt;If you are in tech, learn something, build something.&lt;/strong&gt; There is absolutely no excuse to not take advantage of the opportunities, tools, technologies, and resources that are available and accessible. The points of learning something are to build your skills and to demonstrate to others that you can learn new technologies quickly. There is a concern from many Computer Science undergraduates that they must work on a side project: that is not what I am saying here.  Working on a side project for the sake of putting a side project on your resume is not a good thing, but there is absolutely no excuse to not learn or dabble with something.  Chances are, the small learning project that you do (e.g., a simple Facebook login button using the Facebook API or listing all your Spotify playlists using the Spotify API) will give you more ideas for an even bigger project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you currently have an opportunity or not, the moral of the story is &lt;em&gt;the early bird catches the worm&lt;/em&gt;.  Not understanding that timeless advice and you will be behind the eight ball after graduation –if it wasn’t bad enough already due to student loan debt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://mchow01.github.io/career/2017/06/21/prepare-for-next-summer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mchow01.github.io/career/2017/06/21/prepare-for-next-summer.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>career</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Of Personal Note to Tufts Computer Science Students and Alumni</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While I cannot speak for the entire Computer Science Department, we cannot thank you and others enough for the outpouring of support that you and countless alumni have showed to both Ben Hescott and to Tufts Computer Science Department.  We are very grateful and it means a tremendous lot to us.  I am in awe and I’m sure Ben will be eternally grateful for all the support.  For those who do not know, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ashley.hedberg/a-response-to-ben-hescotts-denied-tenure-121657a23fc3&quot;&gt;Ben was denied tenure&lt;/a&gt;.  During the last several weeks, it became crystal clear that Tufts Computer Science has a very strong and dedicated student and alumni network especially those who have graduated within the last six to seven years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is no surprise that I have received a lot of questions from concerned and distraught students and alumni.  Examples, word for word:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“So, I’m curious, will other professors be following Ben in leaving Tufts?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“So I’ve a rather blunt question for you: how fucked is this department?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“you’re usually the first person to tweet about something. Any reason you haven’t here? Not that I’m saying you should or anything, just wondering if you know something that the rest of us don’t.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Very important:&lt;/strong&gt; do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; direct your anger or thoughts to Kathleen Fisher, the Chair of the Tufts Computer Science Department, to the Department of Computer Science, or to the School of Engineering. They have been very supportive of Ben and to us, and they played no part in this decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. I would be delighted to take all of Ben's undergraduate advisees.  I have started writing to some of Ben's advisees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. Regarding the questions &quot;So...&quot;, I was frank and listed the immediate ramifications which should come at no surprise to anyone, namely:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Angry students and undergrads; also will affect enrollment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Donations from alumni especially from Computer Science will be negatively impacted.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Loss of service to the University as Ben did quite a lot for the University.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4. I cannot control the thoughts or actions of others.  What I can assure you: I am not leaving in 2017-2018 as (1) I want to see the Class of 2018 graduate and (2) we're not morale worse than it is now.  We have four new faculty members starting in fall 2017 and we have some cool stuff going on in robotics, cyber security and policy, and machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5. The reason why I haven't said anything public in the past few weeks: if there is nothing good to say, don't say anything at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Losing Ben is no different than losing a close family member or friend.   Ben set the bar so high for everyone in the Department and at Tufts. I can never thank Ben enough for that, and I am very grateful to have learned so much from him over the years.  Those teaching awards that I received this year and last year can be attributed to Ben and to a few others.  Not a single day goes by where I do not ask myself: “what if I had Ben Hescott or Norman Ramsey as a professor at Tufts?”  That I will never know but I’m sure my life would have been even better.  Don’t worry, Ben is taken care of and he will do very well at Northeastern –they are very lucky to have him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kathleen Fisher and I know how important alumni relationships are.  There is a good reason why we have been throwing get-togethers at Meadhall for the last several years: to continue building the relationship with our own alumni.  But we need to do more now.  The last several weeks have really woke up many (students, faculty, and alumni) on how powerful our alums can be and why is it important it is for us to continue developing those relationship after graduation.  Why do you think I bring back alums to give guest lectures and talks?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will never be another Ben Hescott and no one can ever replace Ben Hescott at Tufts.  A fantastic colleague wrote: “I understand the impulse to vote with your wallet. But I’m not sure that’s what Ben would want.  He sent the faculty a very nice letter yesterday, and he treasures his time here. I think he would not want students and alumni to sever their connections in his name.”  This is not the end.  We all need to step up more now, in some way or another.  I’m sure Ben would be delighted to see that in his name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S., You may be wondering why I did not post this on Facebook.  First, I am not on Facebook.  Second, Facebook is not an open platform: link to a Facebook post or gallery and you will be asked to log in or create a Facebook account.  Third, Facebook posts are not indexed, searchable via search engines other than Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.P.S., You may be wondering why I am posting this publicly.  The reason: it is absolutely necessary to communicate to our students that we were not the ones responsible for this decision.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://mchow01.github.io/education/2017/06/08/to-tufts-cs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mchow01.github.io/education/2017/06/08/to-tufts-cs.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>education</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The BSides Boston 2017 Breaking Into InfoSec Panel Questions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At the BSides Boston 2017 Security Conference held at Harvard University’s Science Center, there was an afternoon panel “Breaking Into infosec.”  The invited panelists: Tracy Z. Maleeff, Justin Pagano, and myself.  The moderator was Keith Hoodlet.  The abstract of the panel as written on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsidesboston2017.sched.com/event/9xRn/panel-breaking-into-infosec&quot;&gt;schedule&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you interested in Information Security, but you don’t know where to start? Are you a professional in another field, wanting to switch into Information Security? Or maybe you’re a Security Professional looking to make a move, andwant to know what hiring managers are looking for. In this panel we will cover various topics for sheperding your career in Information Security from three different perspectives. The panelists - including an educator, a recent convert, and a hiring manager - will field a series of questions on topics including:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;What skills are employers looking for?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;What resources are students currently leveraging?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;How can you get involved in Security (even if it’s outside your current role)?… and any other questions you might have!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a fantastic time on the panel.  Sadly, the panel was only an hour long and we did not answer all the planned questions or answer any questions from the audience.  The panel could have continued for a very long time.  Before the conference, panelists were given a list of ten questions to prepare for: Keith wrote the questions (thanks again Keith).  Only six of the questions were asked in the panel due to limited time.  Here were the ten questions that were planned and my response to each question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;question-1&quot;&gt;Question 1:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(To Tracy) What have you found to be the biggest challenge for entering into the industry?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(To Justin) What have you found to be the biggest challenge in hiring for the industry?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(To Me) What have you found to be the biggest challenge in preparing students for the industry?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Working on open-ended problems.  I am appalled by how students are generally uncomfortable with working on unstructured and open-ended problems. The problem becomes glaring during students’ first internships as I constantly see comments in Curricular Practical Training (CPT) reports such as “I wish my supervisors had described the overall structure in a little more detail” or “I was simply freaking out with the fact that I did not have an assignment with a roadmap.” That’s normal and reality. Generally speaking in the real world, you will not be given detailed specifications as in most academic classes.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Get students to talk through vague and open-ended problems.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Getting them to get experience early and often. There is no substitute for real work experience.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;No hand-holding (I do not do that).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;question-2&quot;&gt;Question 2:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(To Tracy) What skills have you focused on developing for building your career?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(To Justin) What skills are you looking to hire for?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(To Me) What skill are students focusing on learning today?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Taking responsibility for one’s own learning; college is not an end.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I did not take a course in web development, mobile development, or security when I was an undergrad (1998-2002).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Reading&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Writing&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;question-3&quot;&gt;Question 3:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(To Tracy) What resources have you found useful in preparing for job interviews?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(To Justin) What resources does your team leverage on a regular basis?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(To Me) What resources are students leveraging to develop their skills?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/&quot;&gt;Hacker News: https://news.ycombinator.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Nick Davis, Rapid7 (he took my Security course in fall 2013, Tufts Class of 2014)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sarah Gibson, Veracode (she took my Security course in fall 2016)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Me&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Guest speakers and alumni network&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;question-4-not-asked-in-the-panel&quot;&gt;Question 4 (not asked in the panel):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(To Tracy) As you started your career, what did you do to get involved in Security?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(To Justin) What are some of the ways internal personal can help amplify the Security message in the workkplace?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(To Me) What are your students doing to be involved in the Security Community?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Personal Engagement Project in my Cyber Security and Cyber Warfare course (a joint Computer Science and Political Science course this semester)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What: Because Cyber Security is a very broad field that encompasses many disciplines and changes rapidly, we expect every student in the class to participate in ways not explicitly defined by the curriculum and syllabus.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Why: We want our students to be strong in: (1) taking responsibility for one’s own learning, (2) actively engaging with a larger community outside the classroom (e.g., a professional group), (3) be active citizens, and (4) work on an open-ended project. Cyber Security presents many opportunities outside the classroom&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;We can’t teach everything about Cyber Security in this class nor can we show all the opportunities that are out there.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;We want to give students’ the flexibility and freedom to pursue to explore what is out there with regards to Cyber Security.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;We want to grow students’ intellectual curiosity and make you take responsibility of your own learning.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;We want to see students engaged with the community in some capacity outside of the classroom –that’s where the real learning is.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;question-5&quot;&gt;Question 5:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(To Tracy) Have you pursued certifications as a mechanism for growing your career? Why or why not?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(To Justin) When reviewing resumes, do you find that you’re more likely to interview someone with a certification? Why or why not?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(To Me) Do you encourage your students to pursue additional certifications? Why or Why Not?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ask yourself: do you need it? (thanks to Peter Sullivan back in 2007).  Some jobs (e.g., working at the Department of Defense) require certifications.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The dubious value of some certifications is well documented.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Viss/status/851912114008498176&quot;&gt;@viss: “2 people who know their shit and did “real work” before infosec can do 100x more than 5 cissps with zero experience.” Source: https://twitter.com/Viss/status/851912114008498176&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I advocate for the SANS Institute because I am an alumnus and I am very grateful for what I got out of the SANS SEC504 course (GCIH certified from 2007-2011).  I give each student in my Security class a SANS poster before the CTF game.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;question-6-what-transferable-non-infosec-skills-have-you-find-to-be-assets-within-the-security-industry&quot;&gt;Question 6: What transferable non-infosec skills have you find to be assets within the security industry?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked at Harvard for ten years at the Department of Environmental Health &amp;amp; Safety (EH&amp;amp;S).  Looking back, I am now more grateful for working there.  The reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was the only tech person in the Department.  Thus, I had to communicate to mostly non-technical personnel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I learned the business context of Environmental Health &amp;amp; Safety (EH&amp;amp;S).  I applied my technical knowledge to build tools to support the Department, most of those tools are now still in production.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was exposed to the importance of industrial hygiene, occupational safety, and public health.  As Chris Wysopal once said to me, something along the lines of: “you can’t graduate from a Civil and Environmental Engineering program without learning about health and safety but you can graduate from a Computer Science program without learning learning about security, hygiene, and safety.”  Alas, we are still facing the same issues we have for the last decades.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;question-7-what-standards-or-practices-do-you-see-other-fields-using-that-you-think-infosec-could-benefit-from-adopting-not-asked-in-the-panel&quot;&gt;Question 7: What standards or practices do you see other fields using that you think infosec could benefit from adopting? (not asked in the panel)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A standard glossary of terms.  There is still a vocabulary problem in this field.  The problem is compounded when working with policymakers and non-tech folks. A good read: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.syssec-project.eu/m/page-media/3/zanero_login.pdf&quot;&gt;“Why Offensive Security Needs Engineering Textbooks” by Sergey Bratus, Ivan Arce, and Michael Locasto (USENIX ;login: August 2014)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Professional Engineers (PE) exam.  A good read: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2015/11/programmers-should-not-call-themselves-engineers/414271/&quot;&gt;“Programmers: Stop Calling Yourselves Engineers” https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2015/11/programmers-should-not-call-themselves-engineers/414271/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;question-8-how-important-is-it-that-individuals-participate-in-extra-curricular-activities-to-expand-their-knowledge-and-build-their-resume-not-asked-in-the-panel&quot;&gt;Question 8: How important is it that individuals participate in extra-curricular activities to expand their knowledge and build their resume? (not asked in the panel)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HUGE. Examples: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.atlanticcouncil.org/programs/brent-scowcroft-center/cyber-statecraft/cyber-9-12&quot;&gt;Atlantic Council Cyber 9/12 Student Competition&lt;/a&gt; (Josh Corman is the Director), &lt;a href=&quot;http://mitrecyberacademy.org/competitions/embedded/&quot;&gt;MITRE Embedded Capture The Flag Competition&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://builditbreakit.org/&quot;&gt;Build It Break It Fix It&lt;/a&gt; .  Not only for the open-ended problems but also for the networking alone.  Real work experience and &lt;a href=&quot;/tech/career/education/2017/01/16/the-importance-of-side-projects.html&quot;&gt;projects are paramount&lt;/a&gt;. One will learn as much from the competitions, if not more, than in the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;question-9-in-your-opinion-what-is-the-most-valuable-skill-to-develop-or-posses-to-be-successful-in-information-security-not-asked-in-the-panel&quot;&gt;Question 9: In your opinion, what is the most valuable skill to develop or posses to be successful in Information Security? (not asked in the panel)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communications and empathy.  I’ve seen it first hand what happens when someone does not communicate well.  Problems ripples down, affects others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;question-10-what-parting-wisdom-do-you-want-to-share-for-those-that-want-to-break-into-infosec&quot;&gt;Question 10: What parting wisdom do you want to share for those that want to break into infosec?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GTt3qvdTexM&quot;&gt;The same message from BSides Boston 2014: security is a lifestyle.&lt;/a&gt;  In other words, you have to be passionate.  Too many people are in it for the parties and money.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://mchow01.github.io/tech/career/education/security/2017/04/16/breaking-into-infosec.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mchow01.github.io/tech/career/education/security/2017/04/16/breaking-into-infosec.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
        <category>career</category>
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Understanding Why Side Projects Are Looked At So Highly in Tech</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It is no secret that tech companies place high value on side or non-classroom projects when making hiring decisions.  Most of the top companies including Google &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and Facebook &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; will not even consider you if you do not show any side projects.  Many students have asked me why side projects are so highly valued by tech companies for internships and full-time opportunities in tech.  Let’s delve into understanding the importance of side projects for tech opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviews can only go so far.&lt;/strong&gt;  Interviews can reveal your competency in a subject area, but they do not reveal your natural interest in building stuff, ability to learn quickly, or ability to work on something for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Having a side project will open up a deeper and engaging conversation.&lt;/strong&gt;  Peeking at examples of code someone has written and shared reveals a lot.  A question I always ask candidates is something along the lines of: “tell me about a project that you have worked on” &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref3&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.  This is where I can assess candidate’s ability to analyze costs and trade-offs, remark about programming style, passion, personality, and even assess writing abilities.  A fantastic outcome of such conversation is if both the candidate and I learn something from each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Side projects demonstrate your ability to build, your ability to apply what you have learned overall (e.g., in a Computer Science curriculum), and that you actually know how to program. [A bonus is if someone can build something completely with documentation, tests, bugfixes, etc.]&lt;/strong&gt;  Especially for software engineering roles, companies look for builders, hackers, the hands-on and creative types.  The building, hacking, creative, and hands-on skills are generally not reflected in the classroom setting.  Students have been trained all their life to do homework assignments, take tests, and perhaps aim to get top grades for classes.  The aim of homework assignments is to apply recent concepts learned and most assignments are one-offs.  Tests, quizzes, and certifications almost never show anything about a person’s hands-on abilities.  This cycle does not reflect how the real world works.  For most, there are not enough opportunities in the academic setting to put-it-all-together.  Sadly, the result is many students graduate with a Computer Science degree but do not feel they know how to program as evident by &lt;a href=&quot;http://softwareengineering.stackexchange.com/questions/43528/im-graduating-with-a-computer-science-degree-but-i-dont-feel-like-i-know-how-t/&quot;&gt;this sobering discussion on StackExchange&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Side projects demonstrate your ability to learn on your own and dabble with new tools and technologies.&lt;/strong&gt;  Compared to when I was a Computer Science student in the Dot-com days, there is now a plethora of JavaScript and web frameworks, Machine Learning packages, security tools, microcontrollers, databases, integrated development environments (IDEs), and the list goes on.  The barrier and cost of entry for the technologies are very low.  There is a massive collection of resources (e.g., documentation, examples, courseware) available on the Internet.  There are even communities (e.g., meet-ups) and conferences for special interest and topics.  What is certain: (1) there will be more technologies and frameworks released in the future, and (2) you will be asked to work on something using technologies you are not familiar with.  It is very difficult to keep up with the pace of technology and innovation.  The technology or framework that you are using today may be obsolete tomorrow.  You need to demonstrate your value and your ability to adapt quickly.  I didn’t take a course in web development when I was an undergraduate, and I didn’t take a course in mobile development (it didn’t even exist): I had to learn them on the job and on my spare time back in-the-days.  This is especially important if you want to delve into security: most college and certification courses do not “provide all of the skills and practical experience needed to become a desirable candidate for an entry level position” &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref4&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and I wholeheartedly agree with Lesley Carhart on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Side projects demonstrate drive, passion, self-motivation, and the ability to work on unstructured problems.&lt;/strong&gt;  This is the complete the opposite of assignments in an academic setting: the problem is defined (sometimes too defined), the answer(s) are known in advance.  This is a reason why classroom projects listed on a résumé hold little to no weight.  I’ve been appalled by how students are generally uncomfortable with working on unstructured and open-ended problems. The problem becomes glaring during students’ first internships as I constantly see comments in Curricular Practical Training (CPT) reports such as “I wish my supervisors had described the overall structure in a little more detail” or “I was simply freaking out with the fact that I did not have an assignment with a roadmap.” My response is always: “welcome to reality.”  The professional world “is unstructured, with competing priorities and decisions that need to be made on the fly. College is very task-based: take an exam, finish a paper, attend a club meeting, go to practice. The workplace is more of a mash-up of activities with no scheduled end.” &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref5&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Side projects help build your track record and portfolio.&lt;/strong&gt;  There is a number of people who started coding or programming very recently because of the push and many initiatives to learn programming including bootcamps, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/01/30/computer-science-all&quot;&gt;White House’s Computer Science For All&lt;/a&gt;.  One of the worst-kept secrets in the last few years is the number of students who are majoring in Computer Science because that’s “where the money and opportunities are” or because “mommy and daddy told me to major in Computer Science because that’s where the money and opportunities are.”  Alas, this is a major reason for the exploding demand in Computer Science education.  You will not and cannot learn everything in classroom, it is impossible.  Just doing the bare minimum coursework is not enough to get you opportunities.  Experience and track record are paramount for any opportunity from first full-time opportunity out of college to senior-level position.  &lt;em&gt;How can people trust you and your work when you have little or nothing to show for?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not want to put in the effort to go the extra mile, &lt;em&gt;someone else already has and that person ate your lunch&lt;/em&gt;.  The amount of available tools, technologies, and frameworks now is massive and accessible.  A few years ago over lunch, my friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jeffseibert&quot;&gt;Jeff Seibert&lt;/a&gt; said two words that still resonates: &lt;em&gt;no excuse&lt;/em&gt; –there is absolutely no excuse to not take advantage of the opportunities, tools, technologies, and resources that are available and accessible.  While it is impossible to learn everything that is available, there is absolutely no excuse to not learn something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;ref1&quot; href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/20140504203720-173889783-how-to-increase-your-chances-of-getting-an-internship-at-google&quot;&gt;How to Increase Your Chances of Getting an Internship at Google (LinkedIn)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;ref2&quot; href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/what-is-it-like-to-intern-at-facebook-2016-8/#so-what-does-facebook-look-for-in-its-interns-11&quot;&gt;Here’s what it’s really like to be an intern at Facebook (Business Insider)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;ref3&quot; href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/preparing-technical-interview-ming-chow&quot;&gt;Preparing For A Technical Interview (LinkedIn)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;ref4&quot; href=&quot;https://tisiphone.net/2016/02/10/starting-an-infosec-career-the-megamix-chapter-6/&quot;&gt;Starting an InfoSec Career – The Megamix – Chapter 6 (hacks4pancakes)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;ref5&quot; href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/grade-point/wp/2015/10/15/many-colleges-are-failing-to-prepare-students-for-their-working-lives/&quot;&gt;Many colleges are failing to prepare students for their working lives (Washington Post)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 20:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://mchow01.github.io/tech/career/education/2017/01/16/the-importance-of-side-projects.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mchow01.github.io/tech/career/education/2017/01/16/the-importance-of-side-projects.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
        <category>career</category>
        
        <category>education</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Results of a Password Cracking Contest for My Security Class (Fall 2016)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For my &lt;a href=&quot;https://tuftsdev.github.io/DefenseAgainstTheDarkArts&quot;&gt;Introduction to Computer Security&lt;/a&gt; class that I teach once an academic year since 2012, I give a month-long lab in October to crack as many passwords as possible.  For this year’s contest (opened on October 3, 2016), I used three different hash types: NTLM, MD5, and SHA-512.  The password hashes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
bigbear:$1$xJJUvMhn$PnAhcJUFtPrqcgPLTfkH6/:1012:1012:,,,:/home/bigbear:/bin/bash
blackbear:$6$LbFQXixl$Ozskf08sMdjuk2IDgpwwqwTtVPJEid3euQBrxtzsNqiif4wuP7s/CLe7PHeuVmDJLVan8lMXhmqPMvR7Zztll.:1003:1003:,,,:/home/blackbear:/bin/bash
blinkybear:&quot;&quot;:&quot;&quot;:AAD3B435B51404EEAAD3B435B51404EE:E5E47C3D94AF02C2798FBE510DF7F01B
cacabear:$6$D8RyIoSq$T6/L8Nt56.AEf5YZ8oc99sX5WvLf6V5guBWQGr173oDPFSJdxCvCy7qocmLjr9KA7/tyxkQG5pMXtpymOfVRT1:1001:1001:,,,:/home/cacabear:/bin/bash
chicagobear:$6$ZiRsvy9t$tSJPZWkuN/osPl3Ai21t13E/5JLpPote/LPFCU/EUggZB4IiLHHjT.b.zC2Sy8z.Ufh9s7CKbyL3CH4zct1KM/:1008:1008:,,,:/home/chicagobear:/bin/bash
cocobear:&quot;&quot;:&quot;&quot;:AAD3B435B51404EEAAD3B435B51404EE:3C7E2D527B77687A4681B0400F9D9F25
cozybear:$1$8RT.TaL6$gNsnjq9LF2yjgsuBC/QZ0/:1003:1003:,,,:/home/cozybear:/bin/bash
crazybear:$1$8yZuL1Bo$CFgDFz92z3la0nXa2u/Dp/:1004:1004:,,,:/home/crazybear:/bin/bash
daisybear:$1$YGX1Xwac$gmreBVss7axOOcd0uTOc.0:1008:1008:,,,:/home/daisybear:/bin/bash
fancybear:&quot;&quot;:&quot;&quot;:AAD3B435B51404EEAAD3B435B51404EE:C0112B9DB3187CD752A54AAA23F5221C
foofoobear:$1$XCzh81qm$yhPc5ZUrD/Hisol1pmW061:1007:1007:,,,:/home/foofoobear:/bin/bash
fozziebear:$1$syLzkzPE$AC2byibcPyEYOQHOTOAIB0:1006:1006:,,,:/home/fozziebear:/bin/bash
grizzlybear:$6$dOczf73V$QeJe7NqQwY01dfFHVBimqFuQONSswXsQjN7X9cdADLgBQIl5OHiC58sEH6gSSMU8jMOBrOXCyI8B.VCQD3Bs00:1004:1004:,,,:/home/grizzlybear:/bin/bash
jojobear:&quot;&quot;:&quot;&quot;:AAD3B435B51404EEAAD3B435B51404EE:6BE5E7CBB322E62348285DD15F61C674
pandabear:$6$/PgVCL9l$A35Mq3OUtCAH6.itt939KnAfedwLnixmIs7Culx9OjolS0WPIf2eO/a4w0GwCn1ytjaH5WgEz4LPRphmhtz6Q.:1005:1005:,,,:/home/pandabear:/bin/bash
peachbear:$1$hKbWRBKb$Z6u6bSrI/jjs21kCGUeYW1:1009:1009:,,,:/home/peachbear:/bin/bash
pedrobear:$1$Mc99h/YO$wyXQUl4PcL3445YIorKPB0:1005:1005:,,,:/home/pedrobear:/bin/bash
slothbear:$6$7HPLjgWS$7PKyhvnoEXK6aIFmMRlBJ/hnh26EoH/BWe7mF1nuOc7aEW/05gcrzadYsxMpIr9Q2aMRWAK5V4jidEGOpFnDN.:1006:1006:,,,:/home/slothbear:/bin/bash
smokeybear:$6$nZvgK5hA$IIzI1X3pQyqw6HHifJvzmFbqy4YsvfWEUr7ziDxTFAskM0MgWcLnNe2GytOg9fuH2Q8Fj6NqvATynl4OTOln3.:1007:1007:,,,:/home/smokeybear:/bin/bash
teddybear:$1$Lz.US6gS$uzZW7jqRMJyNSImlMSmxs/:1011:1011:,,,:/home/teddybear:/bin/bash
willybear:&quot;&quot;:&quot;&quot;:AAD3B435B51404EEAAD3B435B51404EE:D0B9293D8D9B19C2521035CAD9EEA62F
yetibear:$6$ymHxOcle$Fld.1NstIFNUj0isoNreqAiFDz9lKmsCW4ZHE8MLljOLh7CCwTLsj8AH/qu3bK9pMeMWyIOfvZZyzqVsVxAZ.0:1002:1002:,,,:/home/yetibear:/bin/bash
yogibear:&quot;&quot;:&quot;&quot;:AAD3B435B51404EEAAD3B435B51404EE:A742EEEDC81F844277927E3CE83817D7
yolandabear:$1$B90md6v6$L78BfqeVKpj2scI18FT1y1:1010:1010:,,,:/home/yolandabear:/bin/bash
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I combed through the submissions today: 64 total submissions (students can submit multiple times but only the last submission will count).  The answers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
bigbear:!Liverpool (MD5) =&amp;gt; 11 students cracked this
blackbear:KDI9quo8 (sha512) =&amp;gt; 0 students cracked this
blinkybear:EdRojas (NTLM) =&amp;gt; 54 students cracked this
cacabear:uc12SL (sha512) =&amp;gt; 0 students cracked this
chicagobear:ch!pmunks (sha512) =&amp;gt; 2 students cracked this
cocobear:XQ\Y0VJsk (NTLM) =&amp;gt; 0 students cracked this
cozybear:gpxkr4 (MD5) =&amp;gt; 3 students cracked this
crazybear:c1jkfp5 (MD5) =&amp;gt; 0 students cracked this
daisybear:Booger  (MD5) =&amp;gt; 62 students cracked this
fancybear:ECX[0Wr (NTLM) =&amp;gt; 3 students cracked this
foofoobear:k/&amp;lt;vQC (MD5) =&amp;gt; 0 students cracked this
fozziebear:w7b1vcz1a (MD5) =&amp;gt; 0 students cracked this
grizzlybear:@Pp|3 (sha512) =&amp;gt; 19 students cracked this
jojobear:3scrow (NTLM) =&amp;gt; 57 students cracked this
pandabear:AshleyMadison (sha512) =&amp;gt; 15 students cracked this
peachbear:ncc1701a (MD5) =&amp;gt; 58 students cracked this
pedrobear:kghu2d0m (MD5) =&amp;gt; 0 students cracked this
slothbear:OHMYGODTHEYKILLEDKENNY (sha512) =&amp;gt; 5 students cracked this
smokeybear:allyourbasesarebelongtous (sha512) =&amp;gt; 0 students cracked this
teddybear:kafka21 (MD5) =&amp;gt; 32 cracked this
willybear:M@rc0P0l0 (NTLM) =&amp;gt; 35 students cracked this
yetibear:7QunlW8 (sha512) =&amp;gt; 0 students cracked this
yogibear:u1-1$A#Q (NTLM) =&amp;gt; 0 students cracked this
yolandabear:jabron1 (MD5) =&amp;gt; 52 students cracked this
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winner cracked 13 of the passwords.  The student’s haul:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
bigbear:!Liverpool
blinkybear:EdRojas
chicagobear:ch!pmunks
cozybear:gpxkr4
daisybear:Booger
fancybear:ECX[0Wr
grizzlybear:@Pp|3
jojobear:3scrow
pandabear:AshleyMadison
peachbear:ncc1701a
teddybear:kafka21
willybear:M@rc0P010
yolandabear:jabroni1
&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://mchow01.github.io/education/security/2016/11/06/password-cracking.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mchow01.github.io/education/security/2016/11/06/password-cracking.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Experience Teaching an Online Course This Summer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I taught my &lt;a href=&quot;https://tuftsdev.github.io/WebProgramming&quot;&gt;Web Programming&lt;/a&gt; in the second summer session (July 5th to August 12) through Tufts.  A number of people have inquired about my experience as this was my first experience teaching a course online.  I had fantastic experience this summer and I thoroughly enjoyed it.  Observations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The big differences between my physical class during the normal semester (the “regular class”) and the online class: no semester group project and content crammed into six weeks.  Other than that, the content is identical.  I reused notes and assignments from my regular class.  I created about a dozen short videos, most were on average 5 minutes long.  The videos can be used for my regular class.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I use a “top-down approach” to drive each week: I dictated a real world problem for the week, students learn the techniques to solve the problem.  The students were excited by that.  A few students even reached out to me that they immediately applied what they learned to their jobs or internships.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The biggest thing I learned: if a student is not a self-starter, not responsible for his/her own learning, does not ask questions or reach out for help, does not have any discipline, requires hand-holding, the online course medium will be a significant challenge for the student. Now I understand why online course completion rates (e.g., at MOOCs) are so low.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Interactions with students are almost exclusively online. While I don’t see students face to face, Q&amp;amp;A is done via Piazza, no different than normal semester.  While the teaching assistant (TA) offered Skype sessions, it was largely underutilized due to the point above.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set the expectations before the first day of class.  I can’t emphasize enough how important this is.  Example points I made:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“You are on your own pace.  You can choose to (1) pace yourself during the week, (2) do everything during the weekend, (3) do everything during the last minute, or (4) don’t do any of the work –your choice, but the latter three choices may not be wise.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“You are responsible for your own learning.  A very important point: if you want everything gone over in lecture or in notes, then this is not the course for you. More importantly, that’s not how things work in real life.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“You will learn by doing.  Each week, there will be at most three labs (and a quiz on weeks 2, 4, and 6) to hone your skills and to aim at the crux of the matter for the week.  Here’s an analogy: you don’t learn how to cook simply by just reading cookbooks and watching YouTube videos.  You learn by making, using your hands, and making mistakes.  Same idea for this course, mobile development, cyber security, etc.  “Ah ha” moments are great.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I did not have set office hours.  I did not require students to meet online during specific times. I did not require students to work in teams, a semester group project.  I did not require students to physical meet at the Tufts Medford Campus.  The reasons for these points: (1) it’s the summer, (2) students have jobs, internships, weddings, and other plans, and (3) some students are taking the course from another state or overseas.  Adding constraints and extra burden to the students will not fit well with anyone.  Extra constraints and burden also defeat the purpose of an online course.  Throughout the course, my thoughts were justified.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I had 35 students.  Originally, we limited the course to 30 students but then there was a wait-list –and another wait-list.  I had one very good TA.  To scale the course in the future, I need to add additional TA support.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t go so far to say there are no physical constraints.  A number of students experienced power outages, floods, hard drive failures, and Internet outages.  These issues affected respective students’ pace in the course.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Virtual constraints exist: some students were still using Mac OS X Lion and alas, could not install the appropriate software for the course.  One thing I need to improve in the future: be very clear at what the minimum software requirements for the course are before the start of the class.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It is a good idea to open up all weeks and contents for the online course ahead of time especially during the summer. Originally, I closed subsequent weeks (e.g, I did not open the content for weeks 2 to 6 on week 1) but students were asking to have the subsequent weeks opened due to vacation or work plans and wanted to start work early.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The number questions that were asked, the intellectual depth of the discussions, the quality of work by the students, and the excitement that many exhibited were amazing.  While I was away for most of the first week of August for security summer camp (and thus I could not answer questions as soon as I could), I could not be more happier and proud of the students’ engagement (e.g., answering other students’ questions) while I was away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally before the start of my online class, there was very good post published by Northeastern University: “How To Be a Successful Online Learner.” at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.northeastern.edu/graduate/blog/2016/06/29/successful-online-learning-strategies/&quot;&gt;http://www.northeastern.edu/graduate/blog/2016/06/29/successful-online-learning-strategies/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first experience teaching a course online far exceeded my expectations.  I was very surprised at how easy it was for me to transition into teaching online.  While this was my first experience, there are still lots of issues to be ironed out.  I also need to be mindful of issues like close captioning of videos for an online course &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/02/13/education/harvard-and-mit-sued-over-failing-to-caption-online-courses.html&quot;&gt;as Harvard and MIT were sued for that&lt;/a&gt;.  Many thanks to my first online class for a fantastic and welcoming experience.  We can all agree on one thing: online education is not going away any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://mchow01.github.io/education/2016/08/12/teaching-online.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mchow01.github.io/education/2016/08/12/teaching-online.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>education</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Collection of LinkedIn + Microsoft Jokes</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Microsoft acquired LinkedIn for $26B. The synergies are endless! &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/h4GY25XLHw&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/h4GY25XLHw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; The Practical Dev (@ThePracticalDev) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ThePracticalDev/status/742343361483448320&quot;&gt;June 13, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;According to Microsoft, LinkedIn is worth ~2 of SpaceX. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One is going to Mars, the other is going to spam.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Brian Krogsgard (@Krogsgard) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Krogsgard/status/742361759714009088&quot;&gt;June 13, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TheHackersNews&quot;&gt;@TheHackersNews&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;To complete your LinkedIn profile: Upgrade to Windows 10&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dr. Neal Krawetz (@hackerfactor) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hackerfactor/status/742359530340638729&quot;&gt;June 13, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Satya Nadella makes bold final attempt to stop LinkedIn emailing him.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Matt Gemmell (@mattgemmell) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mattgemmell/status/742336318085181440&quot;&gt;June 13, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Pretty pumped for LinkedIn Connection Requests on Xbox&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Justin Paterno (@zerobeta) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zerobeta/status/742336233108557824&quot;&gt;June 13, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dchest&quot;&gt;@dchest&lt;/a&gt; press &amp;#39;yes&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;no&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;cancel&amp;#39; or close this window to accept this invitation.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Greg P (@KMegafauna) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/KMegafauna/status/742345656279400448&quot;&gt;June 13, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The “Your Windows 10 upgrade is ready to install” company bought the “I’d like to add you to my professional network on LinkedIn” company.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jeff Waugh (@jdub) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jdub/status/742336063985750016&quot;&gt;June 13, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Think: everyone who graduates from college and looks for a job will now have a Microsoft account.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; saschasegan (@saschasegan) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/saschasegan/status/742342770891862016&quot;&gt;June 13, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Maybe Yammer can finally die? &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/Z3byQSpCrU&quot;&gt;https://t.co/Z3byQSpCrU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Mark Stanislav (@markstanislav) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/markstanislav/status/742339053333454848&quot;&gt;June 13, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;It looks like you&amp;#39;re trying to sign into LinkedIn. Have you upgraded to Windows 10 yet?&amp;quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/spareus?src=hash&quot;&gt;#spareus&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/f4485nbuxW&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/f4485nbuxW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; The Register (@TheRegister) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TheRegister/status/742343994064134144&quot;&gt;June 13, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Oh my god&lt;br /&gt;LinkedIn is going to have an &amp;quot;Interview for this job over Skype&amp;quot; button now&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; SecuriTay (@SwiftOnSecurity) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SwiftOnSecurity/status/742375685876916225&quot;&gt;June 13, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;How am I supposed to get hired by Microsoft now that they can see my LinkedIn profile where it turns out I actually work at Sephora.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; SecuriTay (@SwiftOnSecurity) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SwiftOnSecurity/status/742371139104559105&quot;&gt;June 13, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Hey, look at it this way, with Microsoft owning LinkedIn, the &amp;quot;let&amp;#39;s spam everyone in your address book&amp;quot; just got easier! &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/snark?src=hash&quot;&gt;#snark&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/26billion?src=hash&quot;&gt;#26billion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Hoff (@Beaker) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Beaker/status/742365412055261184&quot;&gt;June 13, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;It&amp;#39;s no mystery that Microsoft bought LinkedIn, folks. They&amp;#39;ve been trying to corner the &amp;quot;Unwanted Nagging Message&amp;quot; market for decades now.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Deviant Ollam ツ (@deviantollam) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/deviantollam/status/742386670725533697&quot;&gt;June 13, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;To my friends at Microsoft Research: get out now while the ship is still floating. I used to work for AT&amp;amp;T; this next part will be bad.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Matthew Green (@matthew_d_green) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/matthew_d_green/status/742376049946861568&quot;&gt;June 13, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 11:35:19 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://mchow01.github.io/humor/2016/06/13/linkedin-microsoft.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mchow01.github.io/humor/2016/06/13/linkedin-microsoft.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>humor</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
