<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ming Y. Chow</title>
    <description>Ming Chow's website
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 13:53:14 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 13:53:14 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Results of a Password Cracking Contest in My Security Class (Fall 2018)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Each time I teach my Security class, I give a month-long lab to crack as many passwords as possible.  For this fall’s contest &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/0xmchow/status/1049064581073707008&quot;&gt;(opened on October 7, 2018&lt;/a&gt;), I used three different hash types: NTLM, MD5, and SHA-512.  The password hashes (16 total):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
yogibear:$1$4mcBroGf$v8ApneilDTE18VgvWDBiE.:1003:1003:,,,:/home/yogibear:/bin/bash
bigbear:$1$wxHHsG3L$aHlS./vEc/PEerbNGTWFI1:1004:1004:,,,:/home/bigbear:/bin/bash
grizzlybear:$1$erDsB6Qw$CtTm7jozAV51faPrtbQzL/:1005:1005:,,,:/home/grizzlybear:/bin/bash
pandabear:$1$eFeGh1B.$ysteI0kbYwHAaJYg7gPyo/:1006:1006:,,,:/home/pandabear:/bin/bash
yolandabear:$1$QZGinKKl$mjiuTcAIdf6bfxMKTTkNw.:1007:1007:,,,:/home/yolandabear:/bin/bash
fancybear:$1$RgXw6iaq$PNNEqOsiIMKxLSOHvmkK51:1008:1008:,,,:/home/fancybear:/bin/bash
jojobear:$1$9YPIeyVm$jygTtWr33r.eY..C5JD/31:1009:1009:,,,:/home/jojobear:/bin/bash
smokeybear:$6$FYh4KT1Z$AVDRWEyvasw1xbOO6nrPYJOdVsXYMU58XOrQeXwi8Qts2tGmPwf8HQbJC0qE659iJI0ykiIFX6UUsYm9m/hdj.:1000:1000:,,,:/home/smokeybear:/bin/bash
cocobear:$6$9q3u2Fux$WqZ9V6RQ6w7GNfzedbe1cEnVm3b.XAuZEi8uLDuBoYVsH7Cf3/9M8IkQziuFRnZ/hbcC1JG/1MLyy7NGPxi5A.:1001:1001:,,,:/home/cocobear:/bin/bash
yetibear:$6$/.446T8c$OTqZH8903n6LhUBKpVNtIQQf.so0EprZAym1IUeOLVsZKPMBwb5OgGeLkhJ4xKWLavFrhhuq5N1OEyCFrig.F.:1002:1002:,,,:/home/yetibear:/bin/bash
blackbear:$6$vLklyaUy$HavS8mKYsF0v8Om2XzcqPdwhwywQCzlUp6ZAq3INu9ejYik9BOj9/yzsPTMPy5SniYeWWVrIctg9pVnqdoTxG/:1003:1003:,,,:/home/blackbear:/bin/bash
fozziebear:$6$pT7CDuxB$hpm1p.8c4Q9.dXtljrLhWZ.i4kc2TA5G9xGR.v0RBdJKVz7E9p9esZZjN8Ng6SjlMLPTI7L86o7iXixn2.uYy/:1004:1004:,,,:/home/fozziebear:/bin/bash
pedrobear:$6$uOhp6Hr0$lIZE8oXgf67eZkYNj8VGM1wpbjCiL6xEvuv6rmXweYM/faFKYyRBxW7Dc1X7vgEiNiX3uwfy7HPHBB/wCWNXE0:1005:1005:,,,:/home/pedrobear:/bin/bash
chicagobear:1009:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:cb8538754ecafad5d2ae67ecc709f459:::
cozybear:1008:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:8c5f236d8d0e37ef9dc1d827044d0ad5:::
teddybear:1010:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:c55da69af31a31d7d8e0773c368f0da8:::
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;65 total submissions.  The answers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(MD5) yogibear:L1verpool! =&amp;gt; 11 students cracked this&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(MD5) bigbear:unbelievable =&amp;gt; 60 students cracked this&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(MD5) grizzlybear:zxcasdqwe123 =&amp;gt; 56 students cracked this&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(MD5) pandabear:vulmjz =&amp;gt; 7 students cracked this&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(MD5) yolandabear:kx7yy4 =&amp;gt; 5 students cracked this&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(MD5) fancybear:sx708n =&amp;gt; 7 students cracked this&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(MD5) jojobear:wmOhL3u4J =&amp;gt; 0 students cracked this&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(SHA512) smokeybear:asdf =&amp;gt; 60 students cracked this&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(SHA512) cocobear:meatball =&amp;gt; 60 students cracked this&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(SHA512) yetibear:06mulesystems =&amp;gt; 8 students cracked this&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(SHA512) blackbear:mzpixl =&amp;gt; 3 students cracked this&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(SHA512) fozziebear:320299 =&amp;gt; 18 students cracked this&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(SHA512) pedrobear:R6iLFUgG =&amp;gt; 0 students cracked this&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(NTLM) cozybear:doofus =&amp;gt; 62 students cracked this&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(NTLM) chicagobear:ihateyou =&amp;gt; 62 students cracked this&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(NTLM) teddybear:w7zbyt =&amp;gt; 45 students cracked this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To earn all 10 points for the lab, students had to crack 6 passwords.  The final distribution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
14 14
12 12
11
9 9 9 9
8 8 8 8 8 8 8 8 8 8 8
7 7 7 7 7 7 7 7 7 7 7 7 7 7 7 7 7 7 7 7
6 6 6 6 6 6 6 6 6 6 6 6 6 6 6 6 6 6 6 6
5 5
3
2 2
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winners (tied) cracked 14 of the 16 passwords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Student 1’s haul and methodology:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
pandabear : vulmjz               -&amp;gt; 10milliontop1000000
bigbear : unbelievable          -&amp;gt; 10milliontop1000000
yolandabear : kx7yy4           -&amp;gt; bruteforce 6 char
grizzlybear : zxcasdqwe123 -&amp;gt; 10milliontop1000000
fancybear : sx708n               -&amp;gt; bruteforce 6 char
yogibear : L1verpool!            -&amp;gt; rockyou + best64 aws
jojobear : ???

sha512:
smokeybear : asdf            -&amp;gt; 10milliontop1000000
cocobear : meatball          -&amp;gt; 10millinotop1000000
yetibear : 06mulesystems -&amp;gt; masterlist.txt google cloud
blackbear : mzpixl             -&amp;gt; bruteforce 6 char
fozziebear : 320299          -&amp;gt; lookup service
pedrobear : ???


NTLM:
teddybear : w7zbyt        -&amp;gt; 10milliontop1000000 + ORTRTA
cozybear : doofus          -&amp;gt; same
chicagobear : ihateyou  -&amp;gt; same
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Student 2’s haul:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
yogibear:L1verpool!
bigbear:unbelievable
grizzlybear:zxcasdqwe123
pandabear:vulmjz
yolandabear:kx7yy4
fancybear:sx708n
smokeybear:asdf
cocobear:meatball
yetibear:06mulesystems
blackbear:mzpixl
fozziebear:320299
chicagobear:ihateyou
cozybear:doofus
teddybear:w7zbyt
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Student 2’s methodology:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To crack the majority of the passwords I’ve completed so far, I used John the Ripper and Hashcat. I began by using a series of wordlists on both the MD5 and SHA512 passwords, which I divided into two separate files consisting of only passwords hashed with the respective algorithms. To this point, I’ve used a scattering of the wordlists from the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Seclists/Leaked-Databases&lt;/code&gt; folder, and have had the most success with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rockyou.txt&lt;/code&gt;. Using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rockyou.txt&lt;/code&gt;, I cracked two of the MD5 hashes and three of the SHA512 hashes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I then applied a series of different rules to some of these wordlists, for both MD5 and SHA512 hashed passwords. For the SHA512 passwords, I have been using my computer at home (with a decent graphics card) to speed up the process. Using these rules, and Hashcat which I’ve found to be a better option for GPU cracking, I cracked another of the MD5 hashed passwords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;After using a number of wordlists with a collection of different rules, I turned to brute force incremental cracking, as well as Hashcat’s mask attack. Using these two brute force methods, I’ve cracked another three MD5 hashes, and one SHA512 hash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For the NTLM passwords, I ran JtR (John the Ripper) with the default settings to crack two of the hashes. I considered using wordlists with rules to crack the remaining NTLM password, but ended up using a site (hashkiller.co.uk/ntlm-decrypter.aspx) with a huge number of computed NTLM hashes (since I noticed that these hashes weren’t salted) to crack this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/education/security/2018/11/10/password-cracking.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/education/security/2018/11/10/password-cracking.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>(Updated for 2018-2019) Finding Internships, Technical Interviews, Side Projects, Grad School </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It is that time of the year again and I’ve decided to make one big post on the frequently asked questions I get around this time of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-finding-internships&quot;&gt;1. Finding Internships&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no substitute for real experience and projects. Full stop. The earlier you have an internship, the more highly sought after you will be, the faster you will grow and mature, and the more options you will have down-the-road.  Say you hated your job and now you want to try grad school / research route –very good option for those who despise industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First things first, read “Applying for Internships: and Other Things That Made Me Cry” &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@codertwalker/applying-for-internships-and-other-things-that-made-me-cry-8e49581b2179#.rihh7wj76&quot;&gt;https://medium.com/@codertwalker/applying-for-internships-and-other-things-that-made-me-cry-8e49581b2179#.rihh7wj76&lt;/a&gt;. Spot on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Surprisingly, when I talk to students in my department the number one reason why they haven’t had any internships is simply because they haven’t applied for any.”&lt;/em&gt; =&amp;gt; sadly, this is becoming far too common and it will hurt you big time in the future. It also shows lack of work ethic. No opportunity is ever given to you. Also because the competition is so fierce, there is no excuse to not have an internship or two under your belt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I generally recommend students start applying for internships after completing their first full year of computer science courses.”&lt;/em&gt; =&amp;gt; The earlier, the better. If you only have one internship by your senior year and you didn’t like what you did in your internship, then you may be in-the-dark on what you full-time position after graduation will be. The more experience you have, the more knowledge and options you will have (and earning power).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A former student of mine wrote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“@0xmchow @codertwalker True that, having no CS job experience under my belt made my first job search out of college way harder!” — Andy Haskell (@AndyHaskell2013), September 19, 2016.&lt;/em&gt; Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AndyHaskell2013/status/777703814551986176&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/AndyHaskell2013/status/777703814551986176&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t done so already, read “The Best Thing To Do In Early Summer for Undergraduates: Prepare For Opportunities Next Summer” &lt;a href=&quot;https://mchow01.github.io/career/2017/06/21/prepare-for-next-summer.html&quot;&gt;https://mchow01.github.io/career/2017/06/21/prepare-for-next-summer.html&lt;/a&gt;.  I thoroughly enjoyed writing this and it should have the tips on what you need to do to land your first internship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a freshman or sophomore, there is absolutely nothing wrong with that you never had any real tech experience –that’s perfectly okay and normal, don’t panic. If I was interviewing you for an internship opportunity, two important starting questions I will ask you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Tell me about your first job”&lt;/em&gt; =&amp;gt; The reason why I ask this question: to see your work ethic and track record. If you are curious about my first job, I was a bookseller at Barnes and Noble; started working there in the summer after my sophomore year in high school in 1996, worked there for five years. I had a blast working there.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“What drove your interest into studying Computer Science?”&lt;/em&gt; =&amp;gt; The reason why I ask this question: to see if you have genuine interest in Computer Science and you didn’t go into CS because of the money or for material reasons. Many of my friends ask this as an interview question now because of the spike in the number of undergraduates pursuing a CS degree across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-technical-interviews&quot;&gt;2. Technical Interviews&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, read &lt;a href=&quot;https://mchow01.github.io/education/career/2018/09/04/preparing-for-technical-interview.html&quot;&gt;https://mchow01.github.io/education/career/2018/09/04/preparing-for-technical-interview.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To quote Bill Langengberg (Tufts Class of 2001): &lt;em&gt;“for the love of God, PRACTICE! Even “A” students will not necessarily be able to breeze through a technical interview.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://codefights.com/interview-practice&quot;&gt;https://codefights.com/interview-practice&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hackerrank.com&quot;&gt;https://www.hackerrank.com&lt;/a&gt;.  Practice easy and medium difficulty problems. (Hard ones don’t fit in the time allotted.) You should be able to complete them in 20-30 minutes. Patterns should emerge when you’ve done enough of them. They should also be fun.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also read &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.triplebyte.com/how-to-pass-a-programming-interview&quot;&gt;http://blog.triplebyte.com/how-to-pass-a-programming-interview&lt;/a&gt;, one of the most thorough articles I’ve seen on the topic. Discussion on Hacker News: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=11246917&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=11246917&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyber Security interviews are a bit different.  Read:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lesley Carhart’s article “Starting an InfoSec Career – The Megamix – Chapter 7”: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tisiphone.net/2016/08/26/starting-an-infosec-career-the-megamix-chapter-7/&quot;&gt;https://tisiphone.net/2016/08/26/starting-an-infosec-career-the-megamix-chapter-7/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Daniel Miessler’s Cyber Security Interview Questions, 2018 Update: &lt;a href=&quot;https://danielmiessler.com/study/infosec_interview_questions/&quot;&gt;https://danielmiessler.com/study/infosec_interview_questions/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-grad-school&quot;&gt;3. Grad School&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had a magic wand to make one change, I want to see all undergraduates have at least one internship and at least one research experience. If you are planning to go to grad school to gain more experience or to be more marketable, then you are going to grad school for the wrong reasons. Again, there is no substitute for real experience and projects. When I write letters of recommendation for former students to grad school, the first question I ask is “why?” A great reason is to delve deeper into a certain area in CS like systems, to specialize in a topic. A former student of mine from over 5 years ago wrote to me an excellent and heartfelt reason why he finally wanted to go back to get a Master Degree:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I feel like I cut some corners and didn’t learn enough in my four years at Tufts, for instance I never took a class in operating systems, computer networking, ML etc. I’ve gotten pretty far in the general field of software engineering, but I’m now at the stage of my career where I need to pick a vertical and do a deep dive into it to advance my career, rather then be a general all-round software engineer. Grad school will give me a platform to learn new areas of computer science, and to pick one or two areas to focus on.”&lt;/em&gt; =&amp;gt; Bam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great guide for Ph.D. grad school application (which is a bit different for Master’s Degree) is available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://etherpad.openstack.org/p/graduate-application&quot;&gt;https://etherpad.openstack.org/p/graduate-application&lt;/a&gt; maintained by Remy Wang (Tufts Class of 2017, now Ph.D. candidate at University of Washington, &lt;a href=&quot;https://homes.cs.washington.edu/~remywang/&quot;&gt;https://homes.cs.washington.edu/~remywang/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-the-importance-of-projects-and-activities-outside-of-the-classroom&quot;&gt;4. The Importance of Projects and Activities Outside of the Classroom&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am no longer using the term “side project” because it is too narrow and Software Engineering-heavy.  If you are aiming for a career in Cyber Security, doing Capture The Flag competitions or building a malware lab is equivalent to doing a software side project.  My friend and colleague Matt Weinberg (A ‘08 and F ‘17), now a security analyst at a well known financial services company, asks Cyber Security candidates what activities they do outside of the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, having a portfolio is very important.  Industry or grad school, doesn’t matter, non-negotiable. Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://mchow01.github.io/tech/career/education/2017/01/16/the-importance-of-side-projects.html&quot;&gt;https://mchow01.github.io/tech/career/education/2017/01/16/the-importance-of-side-projects.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are applying to the top tech companies and startups, projects outside the classroom are looked at highly.  I know for sure that Facebook weigh side projects very heavily as evident by this line: “prospective interns should make sure to highlight projects they’ve worked on outside of the classroom.” Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/what-is-it-like-to-intern-at-facebook-2016-8/#so-what-does-facebook-look-for-in-its-interns-11&quot;&gt;https://www.businessinsider.com/what-is-it-like-to-intern-at-facebook-2016-8/#so-what-does-facebook-look-for-in-its-interns-11&lt;/a&gt;.  Ditto with Google as evident by this line: &lt;em&gt;“Yes, a top-tier school or a high GPA can help but what Google is really looking for are builders. Show them that you have a passion outside of the classroom. You can do anything from starting a little project like a simple website, or even launching a full on startup. Just demonstrate that you have the creativity, passion, and drive to start something from beginning to end.”&lt;/em&gt; Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@andretacuyan/how-to-increase-your-chances-of-getting-an-internship-at-google-2fed4ce91b35&quot;&gt;https://medium.com/@andretacuyan/how-to-increase-your-chances-of-getting-an-internship-at-google-2fed4ce91b35&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even friend and colleague Norman Ramsey wrote on Stack Exchange: &lt;em&gt;“If you didn’t get the chance to build a number of interesting projects during your education, shame on your instructors. But you can build those projects now. Scour web sites for interesting problems.”&lt;/em&gt; Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://programmers.stackexchange.com/questions/43528/im-graduating-with-a-computer-science-degree-but-i-dont-feel-like-i-know-how-t/43545#43545&quot;&gt;https://programmers.stackexchange.com/questions/43528/im-graduating-with-a-computer-science-degree-but-i-dont-feel-like-i-know-how-t/43545#43545&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/education/career/2018/09/04/career-prep.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/education/career/2018/09/04/career-prep.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        <category>career</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Preparing For A Technical Interview</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Originally written on July 14, 2015 on LinkedIn but now all articles on LinkedIn are closed to the public]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I review countless résumés and give many mock job interviews a year: to students, to people in their 40s and 50s.  I really enjoy doing them.  People really appreciate them.  I naturally enjoy mentoring and coaching.  It is no surprise that those I mentor and coach land great opportunities.  In September and October (as that is the busy college recruiting time), I am frequently asked: “how do I prepare for a technical interview?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First things first, be yourself. Here are the questions that I, and many good interviewers, will ask:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tell me about yourself&lt;/em&gt;. A dreaded and open-ended question. The purposes of this question are to see if the candidate has a pulse, can communicate clearly, is prepared at all, and is interest in the job and the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I understand that you have worked on [put project here; bonus if it is a side project]. Explain why you did [some function or task] this way. Can you do better?&lt;/em&gt; One purpose of this question is to understand the candidate’s thinking process. I also want to see if the candidate can make tradeoffs. I can also determine candidate’s passion especially if response is related to a side project. Look, there are lots of smart people out there. Passionate people are another breed, very hard to find. For the latter question, I want to see if the candidate has reflected on the work.  As my friend Bill Langenberg said: “People who are passionate about what they do will always find things to improve, whether that’s the actual product or how they approached the problem.” For deeper technical questions, if candidate responds “I don’t know” that is a good thing, not a bad thing. There is nothing wrong with admitting to limited understanding of a deeper and specific technical question: it is a fair and honest answer. Admitting to not knowing something is always better than bullshitting through the response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A follow-up question if project is a software project or tool: &lt;em&gt;did you use revision control for software project?&lt;/em&gt; A red flag if the answer is “no.”  The reason why it is a red flag: revision control is a fundamental skill in software development –to keep track of changes and for communications.  Not knowing how to use revision control means you will need to spend time on the job to learn it (e.g., Git, Subversion), and it is not a skill to pick up overnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How and when did you first get involved with this field?&lt;/em&gt;  There are three things I aim to dissect from your story: your passion and enthusiasm, your intellectual curiosity, and you are not going into this field for the money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you have any questions for me?&lt;/em&gt; Your questions (or lackthereof) will reveal how seriously interested are you, how badly you really want the job, and if you did your research on the position and on the company. Serious red flag if the candidate does not have any questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice that I did not list any “cookbook” technical questions (e.g., “Given a recursive function, can you make it into a non-recursive function?”).  The reason: they can be Googled.  Generally, I find little very value in them.  Knowing or remembering facts doesn’t tell me much about the candidate’s problem solving skills, situational awareness, and most importantly, personality.  One question I do find value in is the infamous FizzBuzz problem to check if the candidate can actually program, code (if a project the candidate talked about did not involve code which is extremely rare).  Last spring, a number of students thanked me for stressing this question as this question was asked on their interviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few important notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A thank you note goes a long way.  You don’t believe how few people do this.  Interviewing candidates is time-consuming and tiring.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are so many candidates that look amazing on paper. However, few candidates have “something to show for it.” A portfolio of some of your work will set you ahead of the pack. There is a reason why GitHub has become a de facto résumé in the tech industry.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you know who your interviewers are, there is nothing creepy about gathering information about them via Google, Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter, etc. It is expected. Doing this means you are “doing your homework.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The converse is also true. &lt;em&gt;Assume that the interviewer(s) will know everything about you. The interview serves a confirmation of what they already know.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 19:57:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/education/career/2018/09/04/preparing-for-technical-interview.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/education/career/2018/09/04/preparing-for-technical-interview.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        <category>career</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sobering Career Fair Advice From the Perspective of an Employer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Most colleges and universities will have a fall career fair in either September or October.  This is the more important career fair compared to the spring as &lt;a href=&quot;/career/2017/06/21/prepare-for-next-summer.html&quot;&gt;many companies / institutions and recruiters are now focusing on the fall career fair and are not going to the spring career fair.&lt;/a&gt;  Having visited all career fairs at Tufts since I became a full-time faculty member in 2010 to say hello to old friends, having many former students and friends working at career fairs, having worked at career fairs, and now having a brother working at his alma mater’s career fair, most students do career fairs wrong.  I’ve been wanting to write a sobering career fair piece for a while.  If I had to give a few pieces of sobering advice from the &lt;em&gt;perspective of an employer&lt;/em&gt;, here are the common mistakes I see year in and year out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You didn’t do any basic preparation.  First things first, read the career fair prep guide put out by your school.  Examples: &lt;a href=&quot;https://students.tufts.edu/sites/default/files/CareerFairTips.pdf&quot;&gt;Tufts University&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.careereducation.columbia.edu/resources/career-fair-faqs&quot;&gt;Columbia University&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cmu.edu/career/students_and_alumni/prepare_for_a_career_fair/index.html&quot;&gt;Carnegie Mellon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unh.edu/career/preparation&quot;&gt;University of New Hampshire&lt;/a&gt;.  The content in the guides are similar but if you do not make eye contact or if you bring a drink, you failed the basics which are listed in almost all guides.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You didn’t do any basic research on my company or institution.  You’re asking me “what does your company do?” or “do you have any jobs for me?”  –really?  You just wasted my time, and I will mark a “NO” on your resume.  For the love of God, do some basic research on the companies you are interested in meeting at career fair.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You didn’t leave a lasting impression to make me call you back for an interview.  More specifically: you didn’t tell my why you are interested in working at my company.  You didn’t tell me about your skillset and what you want to work on.  We didn’t have a good conversation.  I didn’t sense a match or fit.  This is a lot to ask for but at the end of a long and exhausting career fair, I will have met many people –so how do you stand out?  That’s why a one minute (max) pitch to potential employer(s) is critical to prepare for.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You just stood there or stood there with your friends.  Multiple problems here.  No job is given to you.  No company or institution will be dragging you to talk.  &lt;em&gt;You have to make the first move.&lt;/em&gt;  If you are with your friends, it is overwhelming for me to talk to multiple people at once.  It also tells me you are not serious about &lt;em&gt;your own&lt;/em&gt; career.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You rambled on-and-on about yourself.  You are inconsiderate of other people’s time as there can be a long line of people waiting to talk to me.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You dressed inappropriately.  Hey Chris, remember that student who wore a Playboy bunny pin on his suit at the BU Career Fair years ago?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Career fairs at colleges and universities are still important despite high signal-to-noise ratio of people visiting tables of employers.  As an employer, I need to fill needs for a company / institution.  It is important for you to tell me what you want and how we can combine your want with my needs.  If I am an alum of the school, it is a opportunity for me to maintain a relationship with the school and to see how much the school has progressed.  It is also no secret most people like to hire people from their alma mater.  Therefore, a career fair for the students is not only an event to seek job opportunities but also to represent the school well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 21:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/education/career/2018/08/27/sobering-career-fair-advice.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/education/career/2018/08/27/sobering-career-fair-advice.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        <category>career</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Didn't Get The Job or Opportunity (For College Students)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Having worked with a significant number of undergrad and grad students on their job and internship search, and having many conversations with friends and former students, I have compiled a list of the most common reasons why people did not get the job or opportunity (internship or first full-time position after graduation):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. Your resume was not written well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. You started your job search too late (most companies now start in the fall, and are all set by the end of fall).  See &lt;a href=&quot;/career/2017/06/21/prepare-for-next-summer.html&quot;&gt;The Best Thing To Do In Early Summer for Undergraduates: Prepare For Opportunities Next Summer.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. You blindly applied to everything instead of making an effort to go out and network with a company that is one you know you would legitimately enjoy working with, and demonstrate to them that you're worth hiring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4. You looked at the wrong places.  The &quot;usual suspects&quot; in your field are never your only options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5. If you just applied online, your resume and application was probably not read (related to #3 above).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6. Your skills did not match the needs of the employer; you have knowledge gaps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7. You have little to no real working experience to show for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8. You have little to no real tangible projects to show for. See &lt;a href=&quot;/tech/career/education/2017/01/16/the-importance-of-side-projects.html&quot;&gt;Understanding Why Side Projects Are Looked At So Highly in Tech.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9. Something came across poorly in your interview including personality, body language, didn't answer the questions, dress attire, gave canned answers, didn't ask good questions, seemed dishonest, showed up too early or too late.  More:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You came across as privileged or arrogant or overconfident; on the other side of that coin too timid or unconfident.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You were unable to articulate what you want to do (sounding like you would take anything, anywhere is a bad strategy).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You didn’t do a good job of researching the organization and/or could not articulate why you wanted to work at that particular company.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You couldn’t demonstrate what you would bring to the party that would be relevant to the position.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You plan to only stay at an organization for less than a few years and you told them that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10. You need more experience working on teams, learning how you can thrive in that environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11. You didn't fit the culture, didn't click.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12. You didn't follow up (within a week). This includes not sending a thank you note after your interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13. You couldn't tell your weaknesses or failures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14. You didn't sign the offer in a reasonable amount of time. An offer is not forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15. You asked for too much or seemed too needy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, the worst thing you did: you gave up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;Special acknowledgements to Mark Bouchard, Robin Kahan, and Winnona DeSombre as some of the items were taken from them, word-for-word.&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 21:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/education/career/2018/04/11/why-you-didnt-get-opportunity-undergrads.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/education/career/2018/04/11/why-you-didnt-get-opportunity-undergrads.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        <category>career</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Results of a Password Cracking Contest in My Security Class (Spring 2018)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Each time I teach my Security class, I give a month-long lab to crack as many passwords as possible.  For this spring’s contest &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/0xmchow/status/967850845042806784&quot;&gt;(opened on February 25, 2018&lt;/a&gt;), I used three different hash types: NTLM, MD5, and SHA-512.  The password hashes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
yogiduke:$1$Q4g60Y/B$yDThQ6BWKsSjaqMNNbNi2/:1003:1003:,,,:/home/yogiduke:/bin/bash
bigduke:$1$WCay.hxX$wMX2c3Yl0n6rv5ddIXAlT.:1004:1004:,,,:/home/bigduke:/bin/bash
grizzlyduke:$1$B.wi/t0Z$fQo.rAwvW5JCiCCpC7F2Y0:1005:1005:,,,:/home/grizzlyduke:/bin/bash
pandaduke:$1$lnbM4Z4i$gjOjE0BasRIGK0t90YrlI1:1006:1006:,,,:/home/pandaduke:/bin/bash
foofooduke:$1$qQ0SGhrr$qNJ/02Xz5RyHZnqM55AYr.:1007:1007:,,,:/home/foofooduke:/bin/bash
yolandaduke:$1$GJ5zceLI$3HJuSAi4KZ0SpECJ1EmfZ/:1008:1008:,,,:/home/yolandaduke:/bin/bash
fancyduke:$1$CDnK9/E6$ceO1FS7ptGOf1oOijIPw9/:1009:1009:,,,:/home/fancyduke:/bin/bash
jojoduke:$1$9HuHlpfc$ibFX5EwhDScIUWOqsKA4O0:1010:1010:,,,:/home/jojoduke:/bin/bash
peachduke:$1$s3s.Cz2k$nQIZ9RN2Fo8obJ4LjqPBP.:1011:1011:,,,:/home/peachduke:/bin/bash
edrojas:$1$0WxFBCft$e.p0B2NEAe3zaxk1cTTxs/:1012:1012:,,,:/home/edrojas:/bin/bash
smokeyduke:$6$Y75XiK8o$GC2LhHRituUUiZN4ktd5BkUZ67MsVZbXLlBRiy4cHMpLEe5mzrpbhCJ.H2uYwK8P7d12YBeo0WxudkomGH4dW0:1000:1000:,,,:/home/smokeyduke:/bin/bash
cocoduke:$6$Pu9iyDgq$n2jGnAH.y9FpPbg0QuPfh7K0G1ChbC1t8SYhHjIzqXP9qYZW0bCBrcDWSuASD3gUKSEhjCMkfPrLXP.zjCwj0.:1001:1001:,,,:/home/cocoduke:/bin/bash
yetiduke:$6$oVK2jXhT$FaoOoa/hZC1EUC02eV5wPPdrBpHLmeuAlVBKnDZ6y9SPlJIQNR.IYA5EAGQ1g.peV0doX827A/rntRLmhJnNr0:1002:1002:,,,:/home/yetiduke:/bin/bash
blackduke:$6$.X8Oq/..$iSWqEyTmqtJp7Zgu9X6/6v7iy7ezXR7tEeTge5U/RnytN12s1rorG5a3JTLeIL5rX.Xw73COhSz3oxCFGrbzy.:1003:1003:,,,:/home/blackduke:/bin/bash
fozzieduke:$6$.yevPHBB$pZe2PugvY6X4V08ZYUUj7HOHQaHGLArtOj8Ho1HofRtXM5IGjW7cRH2zUOm4opVfCYKI2NY/5vE4XFDsv9d1b.:1004:1004:,,,:/home/fozzieduke:/bin/bash
pedroduke:$6$Q4AmBVZL$mZYFGKmUGYNPwDPjBqhnCKotqdQLb/S9bmvS71WjPfE1JHTSiZd9VMG0hvjQscaHkcXiT3ur.UAtVUcs1TrkL0:1005:1005:,,,:/home/pedroduke:/bin/bash
willyduke:$6$anfRBH3H$OzYRbdfHoB3p1KuEMTv1bTEiIKFb/I7TMaasal0nfkAetojQ0JkkqEEv9i/a38kYqzJgRqzKPYqm0km3o7bBf.:1006:1006:,,,:/home/willyduke:/bin/bash
blinkyduke:$6$C8UU6E8.$aBr7aHZLRkczaHPzuRnGhuafYOoIpEXWr8eu2ZL7lnI608UKeVobrK7qJFl/VYw6c4vF0MIvPR4E1FKYLQqMa0:1007:1007:,,,:/home/blinkyduke:/bin/bash
slothduke:$6$CyRswJbB$Cm04byuMqxJNoytaSN9YO7lbV4f2vFx8M2gZATpjxv9msP2MYv8oQ8NKduoic3qc5YGe4wpVM030iGyQ.TTjm/:1008:1008:,,,:/home/slothduke:/bin/bash
cacaduke:1010:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:f442c6b2efcfa296065eb8e83738cc3a:::
chicagoduke:1009:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:79fddffd223d7cde00a628adbf6bd045:::
cozyduke:1008:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:01dbbbe2cce034344fdc4d28c4c398ca:::
crazyduke:1012:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:8e09a2c04e8822da6157d4c89af9f5fd:::
edrojasagain:1013:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:5a7d64eb4bd95a67ea4feb6783e87aa9:::
teddyduke:1011:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:ff7ac54a5de4e2819dcb3160f3cb9eea:::
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I combed through the submissions today: 73 total submissions.  The answers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
(MD5) yogiduke:oE48YD =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(MD5) bigduke:uqKvwZ =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(MD5) grizzlyduke:wardere =&amp;gt; 59 student cracked this
(MD5) pandaduke:tmann16 =&amp;gt; 48 student cracked this
(MD5) foofooduke:w3chLp =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(MD5) yolandaduke:Ca5S%! =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(MD5) fancyduke:cMJ9cYe9t =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(MD5) jojoduke:BdyuZ6Tqh =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(MD5) peachduke:jY@3%q$M65 =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(MD5) edrojas:L!verp00l =&amp;gt; 47 student cracked this
(SHA512) smokeyduke:8nfJ =&amp;gt; 5 student cracked this
(SHA512) cocoduke:tLUR =&amp;gt; 10 student cracked this
(SHA512) yetiduke:ferraro =&amp;gt; 49 student cracked this
(SHA512) blackduke:123kat =&amp;gt; 50 student cracked this
(SHA512) fozzieduke:Q7Fqyc =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(SHA512) pedroduke:N&amp;amp;8Lgz =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(SHA512) willyduke:sUqQJ3nr2 =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(SHA512) blinkyduke:hsh4BJJ3v =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(SHA512) slothduke:S6t?c?DmUw =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(NTLM) cozyduke:M6E3 =&amp;gt; 59 student cracked this
(NTLM) chicagoduke:v5a1 =&amp;gt; 59 student cracked this
(NTLM) cacaduke:zr4LmK =&amp;gt; 49 student cracked this
(NTLM) teddyduke:Yj-4@!k =&amp;gt; 33 student cracked this
(NTLM)crazyduke:Wkf6Fm3PU =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(NTLM) edrojasagain:HumanHorn =&amp;gt; 9 student cracked this
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winner cracked 12 of the passwords.  The student’s haul:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
edrojas:L!verp00l        Using hashcat, a and rockyou
chicagoduke:v5a1            
cozyduke:M6E3                 Using hashcat, rockyou, and OneRule
cacaduke:zr4LmK          Hashcat, mask attack on ?a?a?a?a?a?a
pandaduke:tmann16       Hashcat, dic attack using realhuman_phill.txt
grizzlyduke:wardere   
blackduke:123kat        Using hashcat and Rockyou dictionary
smokeyduke:8nfJ                Using hashcat mask on ?a?a?a?a
cocoduke:tLUR
yetiduke:ferraro        Hashcat, dic attack using realhuman_phill.txt
edrojasagain:HumanHorn        Rainbow cracks on a large downloaded table
teddyduke:Yj-4@!k
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The student’s methodology:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I started off looking at the password cracking contest from previous years, ran all the hashes through the rockyou dictionary, and then used rule sets. I ending up trying some masks and a huge password list because I was stuck, and finally I tried out rainbow cracks because I hadn’t gotten a ton of hits on the NTLM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at password cracking contest from previous years was very very smart!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 20:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/education/security/2018/04/01/password-cracking.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/education/security/2018/04/01/password-cracking.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Results of a Password Cracking Contest in My Security Class (Fall 2017)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Each time I teach my Security class, I give a month-long lab to crack as many passwords as possible.  For this fall’s contest &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/0xmchow/status/914531472656228354&quot;&gt;(opened on October 1, 2017 coinciding with the start of National Cyber Security Awareness Month&lt;/a&gt;), I used three different hash types: NTLM, MD5, and SHA-512.  The password hashes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
nikita:$1$V4ULZp1H$igC3gPTV3ILlqDvGLCMpa0:1003:1003:,,,:/home/nikita:/bin/bash
chenxiwang:$1$gJVv0xlf$E7KalOk/W4kfiPNBYC/nq.:1004:1004:,,,:/home/chenxiwang:/bin/bash
smb:$1$v2iWpvgH$33JHK0x0VcB3OfMNDZNdU1:1005:1005:,,,:/home/smb:/bin/bash
hackingdave:$1$v.9cyqCo$om6cn4jLSUqLvYAjWkLN41:1006:1006:,,,:/home/hackingdave:/bin/bash
dotmudge:$1$yNugMXbd$lciJyrO3miEEYP3XqxjYB/:1007:1007:,,,:/home/dotmudge:/bin/bash
weldpond:$1$34i9e95R$bPUn.RdUhZdBanLmoQ.dj.:1008:1008:,,,:/home/weldpond:/bin/bash
deidrediamond:$1$QKvrOyAG$CtAVftor1hHUuAyafnPVP/:1009:1009:,,,:/home/deidrediamond:/bin/bash
infosecjen:$1$9tfnfmdo$jgb.GdFQ8Fmi.oUsPiDCU/:1010:1010:,,,:/home/infosecjen:/bin/bash
k8em0:$1$NXtXPorx$Ce9ZvYBQKRTvHd2wvugrG/:1011:1011:,,,:/home/k8em0:/bin/bash
sushidude:$6$dAOxGBKj$Hi79U8/0PvpwWKq1U/u4ISWe9F9qcF1fVnvH0mPJie3mEyAsv7HFZ9c6g4.MKVf.s2Tz/9fvKSzZCxM69D0Pl.:1000:1000:,,,:/home/sushidude:/bin/bash
wendynather:$6$FD4R/9co$oUgADRoJhVqxaARa9QAN/6rF0AUHxhiPyvGACn9DscXr5guTs1nQDY0cAmKsQoBPIt19kSfngTQ6NFQn5LMWX.:1001:1001:,,,:/home/wendynather:/bin/bash
mattblaze:$6$mpJ.ZoOT$1AOTS/HNOomsiUKlATToYYht9UbKmsrur9i8k.ikyBhG5LXpkEQdmYVgAnXVMSZGOHK5tZ6s11UddIcetESGS/:1002:1002:,,,:/home/mattblaze:/bin/bash
apiary:$6$SRnzcyQI$GLmHqVRq1GciikxRJFyLRUbHPy3Z1oSDOTVkOTr/sNBI9KqWc3sK6cROoJJ56noLZQRXutGTKe9T5.I9bvlwe/:1003:1003:,,,:/home/apiary:/bin/bash
chriseng:$6$Q1KGyrzr$NwifTEwMAtnqhkevWV43qmvSQzpn88L8IhJyDtfsz8PomYMDyRcq5xbfkwJ2Jj4NNgT2Xe0wru8ZjUaIEqpUJ.:1004:1004:,,,:/home/chriseng:/bin/bash
scarielli:$6$5M5VTz..$qL2lIAt5RVCZpSGQinwrE6y6oNEwjsDvHK3RxWpip68MXywP8DCVeReyEHJOgY8gg5G3NZFyMqwCrU/wrXFAv0:1005:1005:,,,:/home/scarielli:/bin/bash
tottenkoph:$6$19Ux3/Sz$XMuAt28YmR9w9IXTwODGe0DuWedvO.H05.ct8Xu7xZyj6BH4bTFxmYfYmZr22DTkxvLOXiAqoliJ23smYsJnd0:1006:1006:,,,:/home/tottenkoph:/bin/bash
erratarob:$6$eqnUKgsJ$2AdWNgZO3k1EVtU9Q348kipdc9GJ9Q35MtRKKgNjW5fduiNzbnCjqJAo9UBUjgxRtZwXyztD4CbPPhDQ15mHI1:1007:1007:,,,:/home/erratarob:/bin/bash
osuciohelen:$6$/sFoATOl$X6ve/u2MpudUUVe6zg1S.H1vxF0FIb/83TBOLwmGd6WJA4WJ65D2bqNVJ4gIcNSqsNrtkjnQouJv1xb.J5XfO.:1008:1008:,,,:/home/osuciohelen:/bin/bash
cigitalgem:1006:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:b9f112f18a7a5b31b65d7358995d4165:::
gdead:1004:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:6c8cc3ba8a3917512185052f7ef7525d:::
hacks4pancakes:1003:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:c9b34ac1b90d8f73372fcb135d855034:::
jackdaniel:1005:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:8327798cd80768bb5e8a0cc9159b3d11:::
malwareunicorn:1007:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:267b0270c85cd7b4737f60393f8eefc8:::
selenakyle:1002:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:82abea8bf22810b05bb009622df5c12c:::
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I combed through the submissions today: 88 total submissions.  The answers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
(MD5) nikita:n3*T^o =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(MD5) chenxiwang:vi3%N^ =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(MD5) smb:J%Mi7e =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(MD5) hackingdave:xqksc =&amp;gt; 47 student cracked this
(MD5) k8em0:jwhio =&amp;gt; 57 student cracked this
(MD5) dotmudge:pzadc =&amp;gt; 53 student cracked this
(MD5) weldpond:bcoei =&amp;gt; 56 student cracked this
(MD5) deidrediamond:L!verpool =&amp;gt; 21 student cracked this
(MD5) infosecjen:TeddyBear =&amp;gt; 62 student cracked this
(SHA512) sushidude:9NfD =&amp;gt; 5 student cracked this
(SHA512) wendynather:GnTb =&amp;gt; 6 student cracked this
(SHA512) mattblaze:ssLpz5z =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(SHA512) apiary:Xbnedp =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(SHA512) chriseng:dFCYl8R =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(SHA512) scarielli:5WaNS1w =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(SHA512) tottenkoph:W7ad =&amp;gt; 16 student cracked this
(SHA512) erratarob:@zGg =&amp;gt; 3 student cracked this
(SHA512) osuciohelen:TheOhioStateUniversity =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(NTLM) selenakyle:loluwt0mg =&amp;gt; 53 student cracked this
(NTLM) hacks4pancakes:Futbol82392 =&amp;gt; 15 student cracked this
(NTLM) gdead:Trump =&amp;gt; 68 student cracked this
(NTLM) jackdaniel:TheFalcao =&amp;gt; 13 student cracked this
(NTLM) cigitalgem:Kermit123 =&amp;gt; 60 student cracked this
(NTLM) malwareunicorn:harrypotter =&amp;gt; 74 student cracked this
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winner cracked 16 of the passwords.  The student’s haul:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
$1$9tfnfmdo$jgb.GdFQ8Fmi.oUsPiDCU/:TeddyBear
$1$NXtXPorx$Ce9ZvYBQKRTvHd2wvugrG/:jwhio
$1$34i9e95R$bPUn.RdUhZdBanLmoQ.dj.:bcoei
$1$v.9cyqCo$om6cn4jLSUqLvYAjWkLN41:xqksc
$1$yNugMXbd$lciJyrO3miEEYP3XqxjYB/:pzadc
6c8cc3ba8a3917512185052f7ef7525d:Trump
267b0270c85cd7b4737f60393f8eefc8:harrypotter
b9f112f18a7a5b31b65d7358995d4165:Kermit123
c9b34ac1b90d8f73372fcb135d855034:Futbol82392
$1$QKvrOyAG$CtAVftor1hHUuAyafnPVP/:L!verpool
8327798cd80768bb5e8a0cc9159b3d11:TheFalcao
82abea8bf22810b05bb009622df5c12c:loluwt0mg
$6$dAOxGBKj$Hi79U8/0PvpwWKq1U/u4ISWe9F9qcF1fVnvH0mPJie3mEyAsv7HFZ9c6g4.MKVf.s2Tz/9fvKSzZCxM69D0Pl.:9NfD
$6$FD4R/9co$oUgADRoJhVqxaARa9QAN/6rF0AUHxhiPyvGACn9DscXr5guTs1nQDY0cAmKsQoBPIt19kSfngTQ6NFQn5LMWX.:GnTb
$6$19Ux3/Sz$XMuAt28YmR9w9IXTwODGe0DuWedvO.H05.ct8Xu7xZyj6BH4bTFxmYfYmZr22DTkxvLOXiAqoliJ23smYsJnd0:W7ad
$6$eqnUKgsJ$2AdWNgZO3k1EVtU9Q348kipdc9GJ9Q35MtRKKgNjW5fduiNzbnCjqJAo9UBUjgxRtZwXyztD4CbPPhDQ15mHI1:@zGg
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The student’s methodology:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Mostly dictionary attacks using hashcat on my GPU; I ran john for quite a while on CPU in parallel, but it didn’t manage to get any of the passwords.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wordlists that produced a lot of passwords:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;rockyou&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;HashesOrg&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Also used phpbb, top1000000, Nummer_DB
Rule sets that produced a lot of passwords:&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;OneRuleToRuleThemAll (https://github.com/NotSoSecure/password_cracking_rules)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;d3adhob0 (https://github.com/praetorian-inc/Hob0Rules)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;best64 and hob064&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;A few of the passwords came from brute force, which I ran on NTLM and MD5 because it was fairly fast for short passwords, and on 4 character passwords with SHA512 because I got a couple of them from HashesOrg and took a guess that there might be more, given that (for the other passwords I had cracked) many of the passwords within a given hash function were of the same length.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Overall conclusions: good hash functions and salting don’t fix bad passwords, but they do help – the 4-character SHA512 passwords would have been trivial to break if they were hashed with NTLM (or even MD5), but they ended up being some of the last ones I cracked.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Exact notes about what managed to crack each of the hashes, in (roughly) the order in which I cracked them:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;$1$9tfnfmdo$jgb.GdFQ8Fmi.oUsPiDCU/:TeddyBear
   MD5 – cracked with Hashcat using the Rockyou password dictionary
$1$NXtXPorx$Ce9ZvYBQKRTvHd2wvugrG/:jwhio
   MD5 – cracked with Hashcat using Rockyou dictionary and best64 rules
$1$v.9cyqCo$om6cn4jLSUqLvYAjWkLN41:xqksc
   MD5 – cracked with Hashcat, brute force
$1$yNugMXbd$lciJyrO3miEEYP3XqxjYB/:pzadc
   MD5 – cracked with Hashcat, brute force
6c8cc3ba8a3917512185052f7ef7525d:Trump
   NTLM – cracked with Hashcat, brute force
267b0270c85cd7b4737f60393f8eefc8:harrypotter
b9f112f18a7a5b31b65d7358995d4165:Kermit123
c9b34ac1b90d8f73372fcb135d855034:Futbol82392
   All broken with Hashcat, Rockyou dictionary and d3adhob0 rules
$1$QKvrOyAG$CtAVftor1hHUuAyafnPVP/:L!verpool
$1$34i9e95R$bPUn.RdUhZdBanLmoQ.dj.:bcoei
   Broken with Hashcat, Rockyou dictionary and d3adhob0 rules
8327798cd80768bb5e8a0cc9159b3d11:TheFalcao
   Broken with Hashcat, phpbb and OneRule
82abea8bf22810b05bb009622df5c12c:loluwt0mg
   Broken with Hashcat, HashesOrg and hob064
$6$dAOxGBKj$Hi79U8/0PvpwWKq1U/u4ISWe9F9qcF1fVnvH0mPJie3mEyAsv7HFZ9c6g4.MKVf.s2Tz/9fvKSzZCxM69D0Pl.:9NfD
$6$FD4R/9co$oUgADRoJhVqxaARa9QAN/6rF0AUHxhiPyvGACn9DscXr5guTs1nQDY0cAmKsQoBPIt19kSfngTQ6NFQn5LMWX.:GnTb
$6$19Ux3/Sz$XMuAt28YmR9w9IXTwODGe0DuWedvO.H05.ct8Xu7xZyj6BH4bTFxmYfYmZr22DTkxvLOXiAqoliJ23smYsJnd0:W7ad
   Broken with Hashcat, HashesOrg
$6$eqnUKgsJ$2AdWNgZO3k1EVtU9Q348kipdc9GJ9Q35MtRKKgNjW5fduiNzbnCjqJAo9UBUjgxRtZwXyztD4CbPPhDQ15mHI1:@zGg
   Broken with Hashcat, brute force on ?a?a?a?a”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 22:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/education/security/2017/11/03/password-cracking.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/education/security/2017/11/03/password-cracking.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Students' Summer Internship Reports, In Their Own Words</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I run the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ase.tufts.edu/icenter/immigration/employment/offCampus_F1_cpt.asp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Curricular Practical Training (CPT)&lt;/a&gt; program for international students for the Computer Science Department at Tufts.  This program is necessary for international students to do a summer internship.  As part of getting credit for CPT, I ask each student to write a report addressing: (1) what did student learn technically, (2) what did student learn professionally, (3) what did student wish supervisor(s) did differently, and (4) what would student have done differently.  This summer, there were 18 students in CPT and the reports produced were awesome. Lots of fantastic stories, lessons learned.  The stories illustrate what students are getting out of our curriculum and ultimately in the academic environment, what students are not getting out of our curriculum, and the importance of having professional experience to go along with the academics.  Some gems to share (names and companies, institutions redacted):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I also realized that I liked the freedom of open-ended problems a lot more than problems in class. My supervisor would explain the problem to me, would give me pointers as to where to start looking at and give me some of the initial ideas he had. But he left much of the engineering to me. I got used to just experimenting my ideas, which felt more motivating.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Although I could never had known this at the start of my internship, I do wish that I was used to reading research papers.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“One of my first mistakes was to think that the supervisor expected me to know everything beforehand and that asking questions was something to be ashamed of.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“As such, I was unprepared for the practical knowledge that went into and the scale of [redacted] infrastructure and tooling. On the first day, my team members rattled off no less than five different systems that they were maintaining”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Secondly, I developed my communication skills and understood the importance of communication both at a work-related and non-work-related level.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Next, I learned that I should not expect my supervisor or manager to give me all the instructions I need”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I also learned to not feel ashamed when asking the person who wrote the code you are working with how it works.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“…the first thing to do in creating an application is to make it work first and then optimization should come later.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I would have taken some more breaks this summer. As this internship is wrapping up I’ve been completing some of the final touches to my projects but I can’t help but feel a little burned out.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“First off how important it is to enjoy your workplace culture and the companionship of your colleagues. I am very fortunate to be able to work with people that bring a smile onto my face everyday and laughter into the workplace.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“And by having someone professionally QA my work, made me realized the importance of the safety of the code, and never ever trust user’s input.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The only feedback that I have received was when I explicitly asked to meet and to discuss about how I’m doing.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The working process promotes the heavy use of the revision control software Git, with which each developer works on different feature branches for different projects before having their code meticulously reviewed by various members of the team for quality check and then sent to the Quality Assurance team for testing.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I also learned to ask relevant and timely questions so as to facilitate my initial learning process without delaying the work of my supervisor and coworkers.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“On the job, no one but myself could be my teacher.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I wish my supervisor could use less jargons and more plain English when he answered my questions.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It is important to keep focus on your own project, but it is equally important to get known more about your colleagues’ projects. I think this could help me find more things I feel interested about.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I wish I could have gone over the [redacted] API documentation more thoroughly before I started working on the app”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I also wish I could have asked more of my coworkers’ help”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“How to engage with and seek help from anyone who might know more about something than I do.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I wish I had a chance to discuss the results with my advisor or collaborators from medical poi_nt of view. I believe this step was necessary to validate the result of the project. Networking with more people in my research field is another item I can mention as an important aspect of the internship that I wish I had worked on more.”_&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I hope I could design the project clearly first, and make sure I understand every part, then start writing code.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Besides just writing code, I have also had regular meetings with both my supervisors and my clients from the Recruitment Department to showcase, discuss, and improve on existing features and create a better user’s experience. What I have realized through those meetings is that effective communication is essential to any successful project.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Moreover, I wish I could have asked for help more often than trying to solve some problem by myself for a long time, as I could have been problem-solving more efficiently.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Thus, I learned that I should be always ready to presenting my work to others.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Communicating your ideas is very important to work in a team.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/career/2017/08/16/summer-internship-reports.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/career/2017/08/16/summer-internship-reports.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>career</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hall of Shame Job Postings and Recruiting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We constantly hear that cyber security has a serious talent shortage.  It doesn’t help when job descriptions are completely asinine or when recruiting is embarrassingly bad.  This also goes for the tech industry in general.  After reading these tweets from my friend Ed Rojas, I decided to dedicate a hall of shame to this ongoing problem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Just read this req on LinkedIn: Masters in cybersecurity + 2 high level certs + Risk Analysis, Ethical Hacking, Incident Response, 1/2&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; SilverFox (@EdgarR0jas) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EdgarR0jas/status/897529699290800128&quot;&gt;August 15, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Security architect, BCP/DR, Forensic Analyst, SOC design/implementation. Only reply if you meet all requirements. Seriously????? 2/2&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; SilverFox (@EdgarR0jas) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EdgarR0jas/status/897529959656194048&quot;&gt;August 15, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another purpose of this post is to back up the arguments made in the article: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tripwire.com/state-of-security/risk-based-security-for-executives/connecting-security-to-the-business/there-is-no-cyber-talent-crunch-youre-just-hiring-wrong/&quot;&gt;“There Is No Cyber Talent Crunch; You’re Just Hiring Wrong”&lt;/a&gt; especially the points of “insisting on over-qualified applicants” and over-filtering.  There are many job candidates who &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AdrianCohea/status/899503146153656321&quot;&gt;“are feeling utterly demoralized for no reason”&lt;/a&gt; especially after seeing such job postings.  A message that I want to make clear with this post: don’t disqualify yourself –because the purple squirrel does not exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;who-the-hell-are-they-going-to-find-these-jobs-on-a-contract-basis-good-luck-creating-and-updating-all-those-documents-in-six-months-thanks-to-tcstoolhax0r-for-this&quot;&gt;Who the hell are they going to find these jobs on a contract basis? Good luck creating and updating all those documents in six months (thanks to @tcstoolHax0r for this)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_002.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_006.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quite-a-lot-of-requirements-good-luck-finding-someone-thanks-to-tcstoolhax0r-for-this&quot;&gt;Quite a lot of requirements, good luck finding someone (thanks to @tcstoolHax0r for this)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_004.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-an-entire-infosec-department-in-one-engineer-thanks-triggs390&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Triggs390/status/898023922075140096&quot;&gt;“It’s an entire InfoSec department in one engineer!”&lt;/a&gt; (thanks @Triggs390)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_003.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-on-earth-is-cyber-awareness-and-understanding-thanks-to-tcstoolhax0r-for-this&quot;&gt;What on earth is “cyber awareness and understanding”? (thanks to @tcstoolHax0r for this)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_005.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;someone-didnt-even-read-the-resume-thanks-to-tcstoolhax0r-for-this&quot;&gt;Someone didn’t even read the resume (thanks to @tcstoolHax0r for this)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_008.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-need-to-have-all-those-certifications-thanks-to-tcstoolhax0r-for-this&quot;&gt;I need to have all those certifications? (thanks to @tcstoolHax0r for this)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;this-is-for-an-internship-first-selenium-is-misspelled--another-one-of-these-nda-clowns--to-top-it-all-off-at-present-we-are-exceeding-our-expectations-dafuq-thanks-to-marsella_h-for-this&quot;&gt;This is for an internship. First, Selenium is misspelled.  Another one of these NDA clowns.  To top it all off: “At present we are exceeding our expectations” –dafuq (thanks to @marsella_h for this)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_009.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the only statement that is missing from the above posting is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/we-showed-great-character.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;We showed great character&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;there-is-no-such-thing-as-a-giac-certified-ethical-hacker-certification-thanks-to-tcstoolhax0r-for-this&quot;&gt;There is no such thing as a GIAC Certified Ethical Hacker certification (thanks to @tcstoolHax0r for this)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_011.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-was-trying-to-find-evidence-of-the-job-opening-that-requires-8-years-of-swift-experience-to-no-avail-but-i-did-find-this-terribly-written-job-ad-for-a-senior-ios-developer-10-years-of-experience-required-but-marked-as-junior-experience&quot;&gt;I was trying to find evidence of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kevinkaywho/status/898622008019124224&quot;&gt;job opening that requires 8+ years of Swift experience&lt;/a&gt; to no avail, but I did find this terribly written job ad for a Senior iOS Developer (10+ years of experience required) but marked as “junior” experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_012.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;third-point-down-this-is-what-happens-when-recruiters-use-buzzwords-with-no-idea-what-they-mean-aws--amazon-web-services-azure-belongs-to-microsoft-thanks-to-cthulhusec-for-this&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CthulhuSec/status/900318071713398784&quot;&gt;“Third point down. This is what happens when recruiters use buzzwords with no idea what they mean.” AWS = Amazon Web Services, Azure belongs to Microsoft (thanks to @CthulhuSec for this)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_013.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;they-are-looking-for-someone-to-lead-a-team-set-up-an-sdl-process-oversee-all-aspects-of-security-in-the-cloud-infra-this-is-the-devs-work-if-your-doing-devops-right-work-within-scrum-teams-cant-evangelize-in-scrum-unless-you-embed-with-them-pen-testing-0-days-mitigation-by-its-nature-its-impossible-to-mitigate-0days-because-they-are-0days-threat-assessments-compliance-management-dealing-with-customers-hands-on-coding-and-they-are-a-manager-this-has-100-burn-out-job-written-all-over-it-thanks-to-toughnuts-for-this&quot;&gt;“They are looking for someone to: lead a team, set up an SDL process, oversee all aspects of security in the cloud infra (This is the devs work if your doing devops right), work within scrum teams (can’t evangelize in scrum unless you embed with them), pen testing, 0 days mitigation (by its nature its impossible to mitigate 0days…. because they are 0days), threat assessments, compliance management, dealing with customers, hands on coding????? And they are a manager??? This has 100% burn out job written all over it.” (thanks to Toughnuts for this)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_014.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;welp-courtesy-of-huykha10&quot;&gt;Welp. Courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/huykha10/status/914597824351924224&quot;&gt;@huykha10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_015.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-guess-this-is-why-burnout-is-so-prevalent-in-infosec-thanks-to-tcstoolhax0r&quot;&gt;I guess this is why burnout is so prevalent in infosec. Thanks to @tcstoolHax0r&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_016.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_016a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thanks-to-ronindey-for-keeping-this-hall-of-shame-alive&quot;&gt;Thanks to @ronindey for keeping this hall of shame alive!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;HR: We are looking for Junior SOC with experience in IDS/ IPS, vulnerability detection, hands on malware analysis, reverse engineering, kernel patching, routing and switching (EIGRP/BGP) and sales experience [CISSP appreciated]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Me: I am searching for gluten free artisanal water&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; DEY! (@ronindey) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ronindey/status/972984798938624000?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 11, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Someone sent me this in DM.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(I think the only thing that recruiter didn&amp;#39;t ask was &amp;quot;Virginity check&amp;quot; before being offered to SATAN) &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/6Urvk4LQcr&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/6Urvk4LQcr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; DEY! (@ronindey) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ronindey/status/973294188308697089?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 12, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mother-of-god-we-save-the-best-for-last-as-we-hit-the-jackpot-with-this-one-three-years-as-a-developer-plus-5-years-at-least-in-all-the-other-domains-in-total-55-years-experience-for-the-optimum-candidate-thanks-to-sprkyco-for-this-gem&quot;&gt;Mother of God! We save the best for last as we hit the jackpot with this one. “Three years as a developer plus 5 years at least in all the other domains. In total ~55 years experience for the optimum candidate.” (thanks to @sprkyco for this gem)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_010.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;updated-on-may-24-2018-and-i-thought-the-above-was-bad--even-though-this-is-an-entry-level-position-we-still-require-all-applicants-have-at-least-4-to-5-years-experience-in-a-role-with-similar-responsibilities-950-an-hour--this-job-was-confirmed-on-reddit-httpswwwredditcomrnetworkingcomments4jemkenew_job_get_it_while_its_hot-screenshots-of-the-job-posting-in-higher-resolution-httpsimgurcomad7qvm--credit-to-j0hnnyxm4s-for-the-find&quot;&gt;(UPDATED ON MAY 24, 2018) And I thought the above was bad.  “EVEN THOUGH THIS IS AN ENTRY-LEVEL POSITION, WE STILL REQUIRE ALL APPLICANTS HAVE AT LEAST 4 TO 5 YEARS EXPERIENCE IN A ROLE WITH SIMILAR RESPONSIBILITIES” $9.50 an hour!  This job was confirmed on Reddit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/networking/comments/4jemke/new_job_get_it_while_its_hot/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/networking/comments/4jemke/new_job_get_it_while_its_hot/&lt;/a&gt;. Screenshots of the job posting in higher resolution: &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgur.com/a/D7qVm&quot;&gt;https://imgur.com/a/D7qVm&lt;/a&gt;.  Credit to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/J0hnnyXm4s/status/999653774238117889&quot;&gt;@J0hnnyXm4s&lt;/a&gt; for the find.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hos_017.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hall of Shame Job Posting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;addendum&quot;&gt;Addendum&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend Rob Graham wrote this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Remember: a lot of recruiting posts are designed so that nobody can fill them - except for that one foreigner you&amp;#39;ve already decided to hire&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rob Graham٩(●̮̮̃●̃) (@ErrataRob) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ErrataRob/status/898015231309262848&quot;&gt;August 17, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there is truth in what Rob wrote, the problem is when recruiters spam the same job description everywhere (e.g., on LinkedIn) which wastes everyone’s time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 21:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/career/2017/08/15/hall-of-shame-job-postings-recruiting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/career/2017/08/15/hall-of-shame-job-postings-recruiting.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>career</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Results of a Password Cracking Contest in My Online Security Class (Summer 2017)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I offered my &lt;a href=&quot;https://tuftsdev.github.io/DefenseAgainstTheDarkArts&quot;&gt;Introduction to Computer Security&lt;/a&gt; class as an online course for the first time.  I give a month-long summer lab to crack as many passwords as possible.  For this summer’s contest &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/0xmchow/status/882073476886089731&quot;&gt;(opened on July 3, 2017&lt;/a&gt;), I used three different hash types: NTLM, MD5, and SHA-512.  The password hashes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
chicagobear:$1$P3QnPJRC$ZiUGVezmZmHP3FwGBrSvx0:1003:1003:,,,:/home/chicagobear:/bin/bash
bigbear:$1$0HXmPq6a$b6SJ9SFllGgOz2dU/J1t1.:1004:1004:,,,:/home/bigbear:/bin/bash
jojobear:$1$iSCIcnDl$GhUJv320ZA7aEkmFlLBRb/:1005:1005:,,,:/home/jojobear:/bin/bash
crazybear:$1$Ojbempgo$5GSSpK2r2McB8pyfhsEiy0:1006:1006:,,,:/home/crazybear:/bin/bash
slothbear:$1$nTQQPLJE$go2/.YC/4evqQKE4fPIiB0:1007:1007:,,,:/home/slothbear:/bin/bash
cocobear:$1$xLkX79Xq$gVMgVkhzjkGODtL79NgLY0:1008:1008:,,,:/home/cocobear:/bin/bash
willybear:$1$RdCmq9HN$YhybIiTYwSjywxTotYub4/:1009:1009:,,,:/home/willybear:/bin/bash
yogibear:$1$s.vVsfIL$YWZ.49mClunDlkJapYKZ1/:1010:1010:,,,:/home/yogibear:/bin/bash
blackbear:$6$xGcUMQHK$eOPlvJwoLa3BIrDwHb9k5g3TyukWnmMgXlG6rXc/JiEeBTQ1GMzbm.6jHsxO1ofsMp.PbTVdMQqKDIlCQcfmz0:1000:1000:,,,:/home/blackbear:/bin/bash
blinkybear:$6$Ga52kSM3$3T6ri0./UFR6V/6ICzMX1wB.GG26eKpP2HhaQUpQKTzKfSwqWaTK4CX8kyjwZZA4PH2ns5oH6SrxHMImg.kfb/:1001:1001:,,,:/home/blinkybear:/bin/bash
cacabear:$6$GSEyFgvt$CUjBn1cspBlxmi0YZbFHs.JfR/6FIzh8RRUMhXIYQZXherSbluLlehghZ3Yi2Su2TazjMg3aRNj4V9mWDyhgA1:1002:1002:,,,:/home/cacabear:/bin/bash
cozybear:$6$QklnyMgo$b0MQ9qJwyCjVG7txLANcH2a49h/f5KcA5eoS82T7IKRJqmGWHqO8F5tadHukuibwoUitj5ctQLVX2DXk94vkK/:1003:1003:,,,:/home/cozybear:/bin/bash
yetibear:$6$.u.lAiwI$ZQ1gWfUkquUoSjgjHQsyty.bRvXUYtuSLjLgZYvlQ.fZz6R.4zHPFqcfeqsaCUBH.P9IbZn4wHGyOADfrbiS1/:1004:1004:,,,:/home/yetibear:/bin/bash
grizzlybear:$6$dslx5A3f$g3OVHjyw.2X1gp/C55bHu.s6WRzZD5Iu5j0/3lCMRfnh.fNzyMArQZn56J2J/tB2EG0iKHQnz62pNAtHBt0yk.:1005:1005:,,,:/home/grizzlybear:/bin/bash
smokeybear:$6$yY5UKBjz$wINjW.wdjzaFHD6ytdOGFPjzUoUrRN1dGtr4iNU93/hTVVXO/pqG18nhopZX/7Koc.A3l2kLSxWhykQUFUGF0/:1006:1006:,,,:/home/smokeybear:/bin/bash
fozziebear:$6$K.BwBqhO$NVW0itQwjECKIbPjHy9b6qys2lv92r6ExvIzSA9dhIUKdvHO223ud7fr7JYLHQ1R9dW.ziMNWX4vd.QfsY3vk1:1007:1007:,,,:/home/fozziebear:/bin/bash
Administrator:500:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:e19ccf75ee54e06b06a5907af13cef42:::
fancybear:1009:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:be1773ca5eccc0102006d0f12ee9aeba:::
pedrobear:1000:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:572954208e36c94da325117731186344:::
polarbear:1003:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:8c1653757cb5205609a524b1b3e1c5f7:::
teddybear:1004:aad3b435b51404eeaad3b435b51404ee:ebb2b64f58ade30183b2155a567b1c7a:::
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I combed through the submissions today: 23 total submissions (students can submit multiple times but only the last submission will count).  The answers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
(MD5) chicagobear:P1rate$ =&amp;gt; 5 students cracked this
(MD5) bigbear:Va-[B~ =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(MD5) jojobear:SRYSQF =&amp;gt; 1 student cracked this
(MD5) crazybear:mrfVlkECv =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(MD5) slothbear:L!verpool =&amp;gt; 4 students cracked this
(MD5) cocobear:CCc3 =&amp;gt; 4 students cracked this
(MD5) willybear:wGPLek =&amp;gt; 1 student cracked this
(MD5) yogibear:rqb3Hc =&amp;gt; 1 student cracked this
(SHA512) blackbear:dave =&amp;gt; 22 students cracked this
(SHA512) blinkybear:zUnR =&amp;gt; 1 student cracked this
(SHA512) cacabear:/|rv]y =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(SHA512) cozybear:is0g0TriE =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(SHA512) yetibear:thx1138 =&amp;gt; 22 students cracked this
(SHA512) grizzlybear:extreme =&amp;gt; 20 students cracked this
(SHA512) smokeybear:B00ty =&amp;gt; 2 students cracked this
(SHA512) fozziebear:PCMASTERRACE =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(NTLM) Administrator: P@ssw0rd =&amp;gt; 9 students cracked this
(NTLM) pedrobear:JJyI8f3MG =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
(NTLM) polarbear:HomerSimpson1 =&amp;gt; 4 students cracked this
(NTLM) teddybear:K-(*4@ =&amp;gt; 3 students cracked this
(NTLM) fancybear:6F2Xx2f6 =&amp;gt; 0 student cracked this
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winner cracked 11 of the passwords.  The student’s haul:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
jojobear:SRYSQF
cocobear:CCc3
willybear:wGPLek
yogibear:rqb3Hc
blackbear:dave
blinkybear:zUnR
grizzlybear:extreme
smokeybear:B00ty
yetibear:thx1138
Administrator:P@ssw0rd
teddybear:K-(*4@
&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 21:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/education/security/2017/08/14/password-cracking.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/education/security/2017/08/14/password-cracking.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
